Heat. Heat.
Heat.
Hello, good evening and good day
everybody and welcome back to the Askab
show. This is episode 343.
I hope you're all doing great and uh
it's been 6 days since we discussed
what's happening in the world especially
in the US Israel Iran war. So we're
going to do much more of that today and
I'm going to take as many questions as
possible from you about this topic and
other topics as well mainly from the
super chat. And uh before we do that
let's see who is there on the live
stream with us. I can see SKR
from the Assam Manipur border. Well,
good to have you. Good evening. Put N6.
Hello Tushar SK. Namaste it sat pranam.
Who else? Who else? Uh real painter
skran
sarji. One punch man. Herman baya skr
technos j bharat. It is atim sat real
radi one punch man once again are you
saying narendra des pandemish
uh bharata is here from pur good evening
namaste akshit sharma hello dik shrian
namaste
uh soldier boy is here swami is here
from Jaipurshi
is here from Pune
Baja geopolitical from Indor good
evening namaste uh Karan Kumar is here
from Sakit Delhi. Uh Ham Brahasmi. Yo yo
yo. Um who else? Shishi Shishir Upadya.
Hello Vidiar. Good good evening ma'am
good to see you. Abishek live is here
from Jalme.
Um technos j bharat karan nalawad
jashidam. Good to have you. Good to see
you. Aishna singh. Thank you ma'am.
Thank you so much. Good to have you as
well. Omnak from Odisha. Good to see
you. Heisenberg Jind good to see you as
well. Good to have you again. Uh Hussein
Lakdavala is asking me when are you
coming to Bangaluru? Well, I don't have
any immediate plans for Bangaluru but if
I do plan to come which will happen
sooner or later I will let you all know
that I'll be in Bangalore. Maybe we can
meet up. Let's see. Uh Gopolik is here.
Good evening. Uh Lish Tind. Hello.
Hello. Uh
Aiit is here from GB Great Britain. All
right. Good to see you. And who else?
Push. Push. You're from Bihar. Ajal says
before World War II. Well, I hope
there's no World War II, but the way
things are going, haha, terrible. Sishi
Siliguri, good evening, ma'am. Namaste.
Critical thinker. Hello. Good to see
you. History Go N9B.
Uh, this is Sag Honeybadger of Kolinga,
Dragon Slayer, Business, etc. Uh, Monkey
Duffy, Jack. Okay, Jack. Hi.
Daval Shindai W KB BKT Kalist Adita
Takal Cherry Dota
Nadas
and and lots and lots of other people.
Okay, good to see you all. Thank you so
much for being on the live stream and uh
let's get going with today's episode. So
before I start taking questions, let's
do a recap of what's happened in the
last uh couple of days, last few days.
Uh I've these days it's very it's very
useful to get your information from X
from Twitter. So let's go to X and see
what's been happening. Okay. What's
happened in the last few days? So as we
know Donald Trump had given this uh
proposed ceasefire 5day ceasefire.
Right. So has has his side stuck to the
ceasefire or has the ceasefire been
ineffective? Let's take a look what has
been happening. Ceasefire.
Okay,
so this is from 27th of May, March,
which is uh yesterday, right?
Coordinated strikes have hit all three
of Iran's largest steel plants
simultaneously. Mubarak, Esahan, and
Kustan, the backbone of the country's
non-oil economy. They together produce
roughly 70% of Iran's steel output. Iron
and steel is Iran's second largest
export category at 6.48 billion, its
primary hard currency lifeline outside
of oil.
So yeah, so hitting all three at once
targets critical infrastructure capacity
and the economic architecture Iran spent
spent decades building to survive
western pressure. Right? So this is a
huge disaster for Iran. And who has hit?
It's most likely Israel who has hit uh
Iran's three largest steel production
plants. So they are trying to bomb Iran
back into the storage essentially,
right? Iran is taking massive massive
hits, massive pounding. What else do we
have? Okay, this is from Mr. Aragi, the
foreign minister of is of Iran. Israel
has hit two damage three two or three of
Iran's largest steel factories, a power
plant also and civilian nuclear sites
along with other infrastructure. Israel
claims it acted in coordination with the
US. Attack contradicts the president of
the US extended deadline for diplomacy.
Iran will extract heavy price for
Israeli crimes. That's what the Iranian
foreign minister said yesterday. What
else do we have? Israel then just struck
the Iraq nuclear complex. Iran's Iraq
nuclear complex. The heavy water
facilities provide heavy water for an
IR40
reactor which could produce between 10
to 12 kilograms of plutonium a year from
its spent nuclear fuel offering Iran a
second pathway to nuclear weapons on top
of enriched uranium. hitting a nuclear
site where you have radiological
radioactive material. I think that is
extremely unwise because it's going to
reduce release radiation into the air.
But Iran, Israel has gone ahead and done
that. So they've hit an Iranian nuclear
complex. Uh yeah, civilian nuclear
sites. Yeah, that's right. Okay. Uh what
else? Israel is now confirming the
Iranian reports. Israel did indeed per
purposefully strike an Iranian nuclear
reactor. Reactor. Okay. Massive
escalations have been happening. Uh this
is um the United States Air Force just
struck the Ardaken yellow cake factory
in Iran. Yellow Cake is concentrated
uranium ore. Okay. So this yellow cake
factory produces concentrated uranium
powder for enrichment. This strike will
obviously have a radiological signature
and so on. Right? So this is obviously
if it's hit the yellow cake production
factory is going to release uranium
particles uranium uh ore concentrated
uranium ore maybe vaporized uranium ore
into the atmosphere. So we're going to
see a radiological signature of this.
There could be radioactive fallout of
this in the extended region.
So they are striking at Iran's nuclear
civilian whatever you know nuclear
facilities. What else? This is from
today. Iran has attacked US military
gatherings on Bubian Island in a
surprise assault targeting American
deployment centers there. This is
Kuwait. According to Kuwaiti reports,
Kuwaiti hospitals have declared a state
of emergency. Approximately 1270
soldiers from the US Airborne Division,
82nd Airborne Division had arrived in
the region yesterday in preparation for
launching a ground operation against
Iran on Kerg Island. So there is that,
right? So it looks like the US is
preparing for a ground invasion, a
ground operation against Iran, maybe on
Kirk Island, maybe somewhere else. And
they have brought in they are bringing
in Marines and and armed forces
personnel. And Iran seems to be
preemptively striking at these people.
So yeah, this is obviously unconfirmed.
The US will not confirm any of this, but
you know, this this news kind of tends
to come out on X. What else do we have?
um attempt to destroy Iranian knowledge.
Yesterday, March 26th, the Isvahan
University of Technology was targeted.
Today, the 27th, the Thran University of
Technology also came under heavy
bombardment.
So, this lady says these events
reinforce her previous point that one of
the primary objectives of this conflict
is the destruction of Iranian academic
and scientific knowledge. Right? So the
US or Israel or who or maybe both are
targeting Iranian universities rather
institutes of technology. See Iran has
actually Iran has one of the world's
best
academic uh one of the best education
systems in the world. You some of you
may say blah blah blah because you know
girls even girls get PhDs in Iran. You
know that girls have to wear burkas
that's all that's their issue. That's
not of our concern. But Iran has one of
the world's best education systems and
they have some of the best engineers in
the world, best scientists in the world
who have been operating under sanctions
and still you know as you can see
producing the goods, delivering the
goods, uh missiles and whatnot. So the
Americans and Israelis are striking at
that. The Isvahan Institute of
Technology, the Thran Institute of
Institute of Technology. So they want to
do long-term damage, lasting damage to
Iran. They want to ensure that in the
future Iran can't produce world-class
scientists and engineers and maybe
target uh maybe even the academics,
maybe even the teachers. Kind of
I'm not sure if it's the correct
comparison to draw but it's kind of like
what invaders did to India a thousand
years ago. Kind of like that, right?
Okay.
Uh breaking. This is from yesterday. US
intelligence has determined that about
just 33% of Iran's missile arsenal has
been destroyed as the Iran war nears its
one month mark. As per Reuters, the
intelligence assessment shows that Iran
still has significant missile inventory.
The status of another one-third is less
clear, but bombings likely damaged,
destroyed, buried these missiles, etc.
U US intelligence was similar to similar
for Iran's drone capability and Iran is
expected to recover some buried or
damaged missiles once fighting stops. So
we are one month into the war and Iran
still has significant missile and drone
uh inventory. What next? Uh the Trump
administration has just vaporized a
quarter of the entire tomahawk stock
stockpile for the Iran war which will
quite literally take years even with
accelerated production just to replace
what was already a short supply and
obviously this helps China. Right.
Right. Okay. What else? In a major
escalation, Yemen's Houthi group, the
Ansarah faction, they have officially
joined the war with the ballistic
missile launch at Isil
just as the war hit its 1 month mark.
All eyes are now on the Bab al-Mandibra.
If that closes, the world loses another
6 million bar barrels of daily oil
supply. That's going to be a disaster
if the Houthis
close the straight of Babal Mand like
they've done like they've done in the
past. It's going to be a disaster for
the world. So the Houthis have
officially joined the war now, right?
They have been activated.
What else? Now let's move to Ukraine.
You know everything is interconnected.
The war on Iran is not separated. It's
not separate from the war that's
happening in Ukraine. So
in Russia, massive Ukrainian drone
strike strikes blew up vast areas of the
port of Primorsk, Russia's largest oil
export terminal that processes 1 to 1.5
million barrels of oil per day. A 100
million tons of oil and old oil products
per year, a thousand kilometers from
Ukraine. So you see because of the
closure of the straight of Hormuz Russia
has become very important. Russian oil
has become very important. Now if Israel
now if if Ukraine is able to
significantly dent Russia's oil
production and delivery capabilities,
it's going to be a disaster for India,
for China, for the rest of the world.
And who benefits? The US benefits from
this. The US will end up as a long-term
beneficiary of this. So this was from
the 23rd of March. Today is the 28th of
March. Okay. So Ukrainian drone strikes
blew up vast areas of the of the port of
Primorsk.
There's more. This is from March 25.
Okay. A major Ukrainian drone strike hit
Russia's Uluga port, sparking a fire at
the Noate gas condensate plant. Nu Luga
is one of Russia's key Western export
hubs for oil products and condensate on
the Baltic. used to move large volumes
to foreign markets. This uh port handles
about 700,000 barrels per day of oil
exports and exported 32.9 million metric
tons of oil products last year. This is
a deep strike roughly a,000 kilometers
from Ukrainian territory in some
estimates.
Um what else? So 40% of Russia's oil
exports are currently stopped after
Ukraine attacked the Pimor, Usluga and
Novorosis
crude oil ports. At the same time, the
Durushba pipeline remains closed and
multiple refineries have been hit. It's
a big blow to Russia. Massive blow to
Russia. So you see this is all
interconnected. Close the straight of
foremost. It favors it's good for
Russia. So destroy Russia's oil
production capabilities. It's terrible
for Russia and great for the US. Now,
what's Russia's response been so far?
Nothing significant.
So far, nothing significant or or or or
reciprocally equal. You see, so far
none. What else do we have? This is from
26th of March. Ukrainian suicide drones
struck the Russian oil refinery Kirishi
in the St. Petersburg region. The SL the
sky is glowing red over Kirishi. What
else? About 400, this is from March 25.
About 400 Ukrainian Kamikaza drones
attacked the Russians last night. The
largest share of revenge falls on the
Leningrad region. So this is once again
Luga, right? The city of Le Vibborg in
the Lingrad region. The strike a strike
also hit a building uh and so on, right?
So this is a continuation of the
pattern. What else do we have? And this
is March 27 which is yesterday.
Ukrainians are now really going for the
complete elimination of the of the oil
terminal install luga leningrad region
in Russia. Uh UAVs just keep on coming
in. Judging by the intensity of the UA
UAV swarms recently, there's a chance
that the Russians will soon run low on
air miss air defense missiles. So the
Russ Ukrainians are going after Russia's
oil production capabilities. They're
going to destroy everything which will
be a major major uh boost for the US. is
going to be a win for the US and Russia
seems to be well um right now seems to
be not doing much about this matter.
They're just taking it looks like they
must be responding retality retaliating
in some way but uh you see um this is
still continuing.
Okay, let's see this flight path of
Ukrainian drones into the Russian
Linenrad region. The drones were
launched in coordination with Brussels
allegedly from western Ukraine through
Poland, the Baltics, which is Latia,
Lithuania, and Estonia, and then into
Russia. Right?
So, as you can see, it's multiple
countries that are allowing the drones
to pass through. There's Poland, there's
Latia, Lithuania, Estonia, and then it's
entering Russia. So, from Ukraine into
Poland, into the Baltics, and then into
the St. Petersburg region uh and the
Leningrad region of Russia. So as you
can see this is a co multiple nations
are coordinating in these attacks
against Russia and one of the major
beneficiaries like I said is the US and
this hurts India and China a lot. Right.
Okay. What next?
Meanwhile, Meanwhile, India has cleared
the purchase of $25 billion worth of
weapons, including more Russian-made
missile systems, according to the
Ministry of Defense of India. A move
that could potentially annoy the US.
It's not going to potentially annoy the
US, it's going to infuriate the US.
So, India is going allin with Russia.
oil, liqufied natural gas, weapons,
nuclear plants, building SJ 100 and
illusion 114 aircraft.
What else? Uh, India's Defense
Acquisition Council approves proposals
worth $25 billion on Friday to buy
medium transport aircraft, Russian S400,
S400, more of those surfaceto-air
missile systems and remotely piloted
strike aircraft. That sounds like UAVs,
right? Kamik Kazi drones whatever. So
this account says Modi woke up this
morning and decided to ignore US
sanctions and buy Russian weapons and
oil. Interesting development. India is
pivoting away from the west back to
bricks. More importantly, what
currencies will be used for this trade?
Yuan, rubal, rupee. If this gets done in
yuan, the US is done and effectively
lost the Iran war. Don't forget Trump
went to the war to save the petro
dollar. So, India a month into the war
is buying $25 billion worth of Russian
uh goods and equipment including oil,
LNG, various kinds of aircraft,
drones,
S400 systems
and uh much more. Very interesting
development. This is guaranteed to make
Trump see red. guaranteed
right so
well
I've said many times that there's a 50%
chance of India becoming a US vasal in
the next 5 years I think now I would say
it's a 40% chance India is strongly
uh you could say pivoting away from the
US very strongly very visibly it's a
message to the US clearly
okay so Let's continue before I take
more before I start taking questions. So
that's in very interesting development.
What else do we have?
Okay, this is about the US uh weapons
industry. America's largest exports are
the are weapons and war. So Switzerland
ordered some Tomahawk missiles from the
US a few years ago years ago. Now the US
said they can't deliver them. So
Switzerland said that we won't pay. The
US have now seized the funds the Swiss
paid for F-35 aircraft which the Swiss
probably won't get as as well. So
they've just stolen the money of the
Swiss and they will not deliver any
weapons as per the contract. Neither
missiles nor F-35s. Very interesting. Uh
there's more about this.
Europe spent Europe sent $750 million to
the US to support Ukraine with weapons
from the US. The Pentagon now plans to
use that money to refill American
weapons stockpiles instead, most likely
because of the war against Iran. Even US
officials admit that it's unclear if
European countries fully understand
where the money could actually go. Okay.
So, the Pentagon notified Congress on
Monday that it intended to divert about
$750 million in funding provided by NATO
countries to restock the US military's
own inventories rather than send
additional assistance to Ukraine as per
according to two US officials.
So the Europeans
sent this money to the US so that the US
can send them weapons that can be
supplied to Ukraine. And the Europeans
are paying out of their own pocket. So
the Americans have said, "Okay, we'll
keep this money and we'll use this money
uh to to refill US weapons inventories
for themselves." But that's not your
money, right? Doesn't matter. Doesn't
matter. It's NATO. It's a vas. It's a
bunch of vasals. Who cares? Fantastic,
fantastic, fantastic.
So, Trump has now single-handedly killed
the entire US arms industry. Every
country now knows that if you buy
weapons from the US, Trump could simply
decide not to send them to you. Who in
their right mind would buy weapons from
the US going forward? It's a good
question. Okay, here's one more before
we start taking questions. Okay. Um,
Denmark secretly deployed soldiers to
Greenland prepared to blow up airport
runways to stop a US invasion. So Trump
has been threatening to invade
Greenland, right? And to annex
Greenland. So the so Denmark secretly
deployed soldiers to Greenland and they
were prepared prepared to blow up
airport runways to stop an American
invasion. They brought blood supplies to
treat the wounded. France, Germany,
Norway and Sweden quietly coordinated
against the Americans. This was not a
drill. This was America's closest vasals
preparing to fight Americans. Right?
So the US seems to well doesn't seem to
be trusted a lot by its own vasals these
days. Right? So that's a quick update of
what's been happening. Now let's uh now
let's take some questions. Let's begin
with the questions. What questions do we
have? All right. This is a question by
Anikit.
uh if Houthis block the Bab al-Mandde
then would India take action against
them that's first secondly India started
buying gas from Russia and Iran after
years your take on that and three views
on trans bill 2026 okay Houthis are
could block the straight of Babal Mad
it's not happened yet but they could
they could they are capable of doing it
and the Americans tried a year a full
year of air strikes against the Houthis
could not force the Houthies to open it
until eventually there was an agreement
between between the two and still the
agreement was such that Iranian Israeli
ships could not transit the straight of
Hormos and that is still effective so
the US isn't able to dislodge the
Houthies and defeat them so if the
Houthis go ahead and block the straight
of Babal Mande should India take against
action against them India should stay
out of the matter the American stride
for over a year they launched hundreds
of air strikes against the Houthis they
lost aircraft They lo lost drones. Their
ships were targeted by Houthi missiles
and drones. This is not our war. It's
going to hurt us. Yes, I know it's going
to hurt us. But we don't want to put our
naval assets, our our navy in harm's
way. India should stay out of this
matter. We should look for alternate
means of receiving oil, gas, whatever.
We should not get involved in this war
in any way whatsoever. Okay. Secondly,
India started buying gas from Russia and
Iran after years. What's my take? Good.
Good. It's a good thing. Sir, your views
on trans bill 2026. I have no idea what
is a trans bill. Trans bill 2026. What
is that? Let's uh take a look, shall we?
Trans bill 2026. Let's see. Trans bill
2026.
What is that?
Transgender persons amendment. I have no
idea what that is. I I have not looked
into it. I I'm I'm not going to I'm not
going to do the research right now. I
have no idea. So, sorry. Anik once again
says, "Don't you think that Iran's
foreign policy after 1979 was emotional
and unrealistic? They antagonized the US
by capturing diplomats. Israel Jews
don't have the right to live. Condemned
USSR's invasion of Afghanistan. Tried to
poke in India's internal matters by
Kashmir at least verbally." Words of
somebody.
Um, so
Iran's foreign policy after 79 was
emotional and unrealistic. Yes or no?
Initially, you could say it was
unrealistic and and emotional. I think
there was no need to antagonize the
United States by capturing diplomats.
We're talking about 1979. We not talking
about 2010. We're talking about 1979.
That's ancient history.
Okay? So, yes, that was stupid. But
Iran, the Islamic Republic of Iran was
just born at the time. There was still
chaos and anarchy on the streets.
There was a lot of hotheaded young
people around who were doing all kinds
of nasty things.
And at that time there was not a stable
government in place properly that
controlled the whole nation and you know
could stop people from doing things. Uh
so there were elements
in Iran
obviously related to the revolutionaries
who did this who captured the embassy
and more than 400 Americans were taken
hostage and this went on for a very long
time more than 400 days I don't remember
the exact day number of days but yeah so
that was stupid it was unnecessarily
antagonistic unnecessarily they
unnecessarily antagonized the United
States yes I completely agree with that
now what But the rest of the question,
Israel, Jews don't have the right to
live. Well, that is obviously no nation
can accept that, right? Uh is Iran
saying that Israel and Jews have no
right to live? I don't know about Jews,
but they said that Israel doesn't have
the right to exist. Well, that obviously
is
well, that's not going to fly with
anybody, right? So, that but it's an
ideological position that they've taken.
And a lot of Arabic nations also have in
the past had the same outlook.
Once Israel was formed, every single
neighbor of Israel, Arabic nations all
attacked attacked Israel with the
objective of, you know, of of ending
Israel's existence. So they also believe
that Israel has no right to live. Right?
Today that's a different story. in the
situation in the in the region and a lot
of these nations are you know on
reasonably good terms with with Israel
because they're all US vasals and Iran
has stuck to the original position.
So yeah obviously that's going to be a
problem for Israel and that's why we
have enmity between Iran and Israel. Uh
USSR's invasion of Afghanistan I don't
remember what was the situation with
that. I don't know what Iran's stance
was in that situation. probably US sir
would have uh
maybe Iran condemned that okay tried to
poke in India's internal matters with
like Kashmir verbally yeah verbally
they've done that but they have taken no
actual action that hurts India's
interests but verbally they have the
position that you know Kashmir is blah
blah blah all that stuff which is
annoying very annoying even for me but I
keep words and actions separate I ignore
words I look at actions so yes it's
annoying
Even I can't always disregard words. It
annoys me as well. But from the
perspective of actions, they have taken
no actions that are pro Pakistan and
anti-India. Right. So yeah, that's my um
yeah that's my analysis.
Okay. Pratt, good evening says, "Isn't
Donald J. Trump sounding insane? Mental
health issue."
He well he's sounding like himself.
Is he sounding a little more unhinged?
What has he said of late? I I saw a
couple of clips earlier today of Donald
J. Trump speaking, you know, press
conference or or speech or whatever it
was in public. Obviously, in one of
these clips, he is saying that I don't
like people who are super successful.
I like to be in the company of losers.
That makes me feel good.
I don't want to listen to other people's
success stories. I want people who will
listen to my success stories. I'm
paraphrasing. It may not be the exact
words, but he says that he prefers the
company of losers. He doesn't like to be
in the presence of very successful
people. Well, that's a very interesting
psychological data point about Donald
Trump.
Yeah. He likes to be in the company of
losers. Makes him happy. He doesn't like
other people's success. Okay. Okay.
Interesting. Another thing he said was
about uh Muhammad bin Salman.
So he was speaking in a press
conference. He was answering questions
or some something, right? And he's
talking about Muhammad bin Salman who is
the crown prince of Saudi Arabia, the
kingdom of Saudi Arabia. He will be the
next king of Saudi Arabia. And he's
talking about Muhammad bin Salman and
saying,
and these are his words, not mine. I
don't use such language,
at least not here.
He says that Muhammad bin Salman has
been kissing my ass.
That's what he said. That those are the
words ass kissing or kissing ass or
whatever he said. Yeah. That is so
incredibly disrespectful
of the the de facto
leader of a sovereign nation.
So Trump, if you are on good terms with
Trump, he's going to make it a point to
humiliate you, to disrespect you in
front of the entire world.
He respects only those who are his
enemies or opponents.
If you're on good terms with him, he's
going to drag you through the mud. He
does that to everybody. He does that to
Emanuel Mak. He does it to the the
leader of England, whoever it is, Sar
guy. uh whether it is u the the leader
of Canada, whether it is whoever,
he he will speak respectfully only about
his enemies,
right?
So it's it's if you're a world leader,
it makes a lot of sense to stay as far
away as possible from Trump. Limit your
communications with him and never ever
be in the same room with the same with
this guy. And that's a policy Mr. Modi
has adopted.
Okay? And see we don't want to see our
prime minister being spoken about in the
in the same manner because our prime
minister you may like him or not that's
your problem but he represents our
country and if Trump is insulting and
humiliating our prime minister he's
humiliating us and insulting us. Okay
understand that that's what it means. So
Trump is certain seriously certainly
sounding a little more unhinged than
usual these days.
But I think that's just Trump. I I've
I've known Trump for a long time. Not
personally, but I've been observing and
watching him for more than 25 years.
Okay.
And this is him. This is what Trump is
like. Uh I'm not sure there's any mental
health issue. He's definitely more
present than Biden.
But yeah, he's also pretty elderly. He's
getting on in age and maybe that's why
you can see more of his true personality
shining through from time to time.
Okay. Aniket says one is it not in
India's long-term interest that Iran
does not get nukes. Yes, they are not
enemy of India but now but their
theology
is it not good for world that not no
more nations get nukes
okay let's deal with that question first
there are three two more questions so is
it not in India's long-term interest
that is that Iran does not get nukes
they're not our enemy right now but
their theology
their the is an Islamic nation shia
Muslims okay and is it not good for the
world that no more nations get nukes.
Okay, let's imagine a scenario
hypothetical scenario
where Iran has acquired nuclear weapons.
Is it bad for India?
See, we have a nation, the temporary
artificial nation of Pakistan that has
nukes and they are aimed at India.
Now imagine this. See look at the map.
Okay. Um the map is is a great friend of
ours. So let's let's take a look at the
map. So Pakistan is our enemy. They seek
to see us dead. They seek to see us
destroyed. I'm not talking about the
people of Pakistan. Many of them are
nice people I'm sure. But I'm talking
about the nation of Pakistan who have
always treated us as as an enemy. So if
Pakistan has nukes and those nukes are
aimed at us and Pak and Iran is still
the current government of Iran which is
not a friend of Pakistan and Iran
acquires nuclear weapons. Well, that's
going to be an issue for Pakistan. It's
going to be a big issue for Pakistan and
Pakistan is going to then have to aim
half of their nukes to towards Iran,
right? So it becomes a problem for
Pakistan because Pakistan and Iran are
not friends, they are enemies.
A couple of years ago they launched
missiles at each other. Iran has
repeatedly in the past accused Pakistan
of uh harboring terrorists and of
crossber terrorism.
Same as Afghanistan. Nobody likes
Pakistan. So Iran doesn't like Pakistan.
The Islamic Republic of Pakis of Iran
does not like the Islamic Republic of
Pakistan. Okay? They are enemies. So if
Iran acquires nukes, it's bad for
Pakistan. Is it bad for India? Not
necessarily. We have no issues with
Iran. We don't have territorial disputes
with Iran. We don't seek to destroy
Iran. We don't seek a regime change in
Iran. We seek no, we have no issues with
Iran as such. Iran will of course become
way more assertive if it gets nukes and
they have missiles that essentially can
reach anywhere within India, anywhere
within most of Europe as well. So if
Iran acquires nukes, it's going to be a
problem for everybody and they will have
to then deal with Iran more carefully
the way they have to deal with other
nuclearpowered nations more carefully.
So if Iran acquires nukes, I don't see
it as being a problem for India,
it's going to be mostly a problem for
Pakistan, for Israel as well, and for
the US and for the other nations in the
neighborhood. As long as you have good
relations with Iran, there will be no
issue for you. So Iran's nukes can reach
China as well. I'm not sure if they can
reach Beijing, but they can reach at
least half of China, if not more. So
it's not like it's an issue for India. I
don't see it that way. It may make the
region a little more stable. It may
actually be, you know, a really bad
thing for Pakistan. Okay, next question.
DAC uh Okay, what about um is it is it
not good for the world that no more
nations get nukes?
If no more nations get nukes, then it's
only a small it's essentially only a
couple of strong nations that can bully
everybody else. But if you have 15
nations with nukes, hypothetically, I'm
not saying we should have it. Then I
think that will be a truly multi
multipolar world. A multipolar world is
not a world where everyone has the
slogan of multipolarity. A multipolar
world is a nation in which multiple
nations are genuinely sovereign and
can't be bullied. That can only happen
if you have 15 20 nations with nuclear
nuclear weapons. Okay. Is it bad for the
world? Well, it is what it is. Yeah.
After what's happened now, I think many
nations will seek to acquire nuclear
weapons. And if you have decent
engineers and scientists, it's not that
hard as long as you have access to
facile material, the specific isotope of
uranium.
Uh DAC approves 60 gatak with caviar
engine. Well, I think that's great,
right? The gatak is the uh aura program
which is now called the gatak program.
It's an un unmanned stealthy uh fighter
aircraft. It can also do bombing runs
and it's a stealthy aircraft. It's a
stealth aircraft. So you can't really
it's it's like the American stealth
aircraft, right? And uh since 60 of
these have been approved, it means that
it's it's performing performing well in
trials. So 60 of these aircraft are
going to come into production whatever
time it takes with cavary engines. the
non non with the dry version of the
cover engine which is the non
afterburner version I think it's
fantastic let's induct these 60 aircraft
test them out uh wherever possible and
improve upon them and have 60 more and
so on right I think it's great it's
fantastic news um Israel hits 75% of
Iran's total steel manufacturing capa
capacity I discussed that it's it's
obviously the objective is to send Iran
back into the stone age they want to
destroy Iran completely whether it's
Israel whether it's the US they were
saying They want a regime change in Iran
and they want to liberate the people of
Iran. Well, you're not going to liberate
the people of Iran by destroying the
nation's industrial capabilities, right?
So, yeah. Yeah. But that's war. That's
war for you. It's it's nasty.
Okay. Adita Tak says, "Do you think if
Iran government survives, this would be
a bigger humiliation for the US than
Vietnam?"
Will it be a bigger humiliation for the
US than Vietnam is a question that has
to be approached from multiple
perspectives.
See, right now the Americans have not
attempted thus far, as far as I know, um
8:39 p.m.
on the 28th of March. Thus far as I
know, the Americans have not yet
launched or attempted a ground invasion
of any part of Iran.
Um ground invasions are bloody. Iran is
a well-defended country and uh a ground
invasion will is guaranteed
to generate lots of casualties from the
attacker side and from the defender side
as well.
So I don't know how many American armed
forces personnel have thus far lost
their lives in this war but in Vietnam
the number was very very high. Okay,
that's one perspective. So, let's let's
find out. Okay,
how many Americans lost their life in
the Vietnam War?
So, okay, officially
uh 58,000
military fatal casualties.
Okay, that's a very large number.
So
in this war the official figure is like
15 people have died or something 15
soldiers or whatever have died. That's
what the America Americans are claiming.
The actual number is possibly much
higher but
you don't reveal that right? You can
reveal that long after the war is over
but right now you don't reveal it
because otherwise it will you know boost
the morale of your enemy. So, so
officially about 15 or so soldiers,
American soldiers have died. So, that
way hum Vietnam is a much bigger
humiliation and of course the Vietnam
war lasted more than a decade, right?
And the Americans eventually had to move
out of Vietnam and they had to evacuate
their embassy in a very visible
humiliating way. Those things haven't
happened thus far. So, I think Vietnam
is the biggest humiliation the Americans
have experienced. I don't think this
Iran war is uh u thus far anything
comparable to that. The the war against
Iran is not going the way they expected.
Um it is very clear that they will not
be successful in achieve achieving a
regime change anytime soon. Right? Even
with nuclear weapons potentially being
used, which I hope never happens, but
even if we consider the hypothetical
scenario, it's still unlikely that they
will achieve a regime change. So um if
they don't win this war, it's a
humiliation because the US is the
biggest badass nation in the world,
right? And Iran is the small little
regional nation. So the US expected
they'll walk over Iran. That's not
happened. It's been a month and the
Iranians are still hitting back, right?
Iran is being smashed for sure. is being
pounded. You know, nuclear plants, steel
plants, schools,
universities, everything is being
destroyed, is being destroyed, but Iran
is still fighting back and hitting hard.
So, it doesn't look like the regime
change is possible anytime soon. And if
the Americans can't open the straight of
hormones and can't do a regime change in
Iran, then what have they achieved is
the big question. So, if the war ends
the way things are right now, it's going
to be a defeat for the US or at least
not a success for them. It's going to be
humiliating for Trump especially, but I
don't think at this point in time it is
a bigger humiliation than Vietnam.
Vietnam was a massive humiliation. This
is not comparable to that at this point
in time.
WYKT says 29 US troops got injured in a
recent attack on Saudi Arabian base.
Yes.
Okay. Let's see what Google has to say
about that. Yes, that's true. I I saw
the I saw the news.
Was there a recent attack on a Saudi
Arabian military base in which American
troops got injured?
Yes. 27 28 March, Iranian missile and
drone attack on Prince Sultan air base
in Saudi Arabia injured at least 10 to
12 US service members. Two Americans uh
were seriously injured etc etc.
They're not sure. Okay. How many uh dive
deeper dive deeper? Okay.
Uh blah blah blah is going to go into
that.
Okay. Multiple US Air Force refueling
aircraft were damaged. Damaged means
destroyed. Okay. Damaged means destroyed
over here. So multiple aircraft of this
category were destroyed on the flight
line during the assault and also damaged
to an E3 Century Awax command and
control aircraft. Okay. Okay, so this is
the second confirmed Iranian strike on
the Prince Sultan air base since this
conflict began
and about 13 official officially 13
American uh personnel have been killed
in the region and 300 have been injured.
Okay. Right. So as I said, thank you for
drawing our attention to this, sir. And
as I said, the Iranians are hitting back
hard.
WB BKT says Houthis have now joined the
war is our friend Donald Trump cooked.
Um
the Houthis joining the war is a
complication and it can be potentially
disastrous if they succeed in closing
the straight of Babal Mandib once again.
So it doesn't mean Donald Trump is
cooked but it may actually be good for
him because then the world will have to
somehow or the other depend on oil
coming from the US. It's going to put
India and China under pressure,
significant pressure. Things will go bad
in India and China if both the straits
are closed. In case some of you are not
aware what this strait is, the strait of
Bab al- Mandib, let's go there. There
are two major straits that we are
concerned about. One is obviously the
straight of Ahuram Mazda or Hormuz which
is here. Okay. between the Persian Gulf
and the U Gulf of Oman. And then you
have the straight of Babal Mande which
is another major geographical geographic
choke point which connects the Red Sea
to the to the Gulf of Adan and this is a
very narrow place and the Houthis have
in the past completely closed this
straight for more than a year. So they
are certainly capable of doing that
again. The question is if they close the
straight of Babal Mand how long can they
keep it closed? Because the Houthis, the
Ansar Allah faction in Yemen, they
depend on Iran for supplies of missiles,
rockets and whatnot. So if they run low
on those supplies, then they may not be
able to close this trait uh
indefinitely, but they can at least
close it for a while, right? And that
could be a problem. So yes, that
complication could be on its way towards
us.
Okay.
Shishi says, "What happened to your
right eye? Are you feeling okay? My
right eye is completely fine. Did
something happen? I'm not sure. It's
fine. It's fine. Thank you for the
concern, ma'am. It's perfectly fine."
Pranjal Torres says, "Why Iran? Why Iran
allowed Pakistani tankers to cross the
straight of Hormuz?
Maybe tactical reasons. You know, thus
far Pakistan is not involved in the war
officially. So let them cross and you
can still at this point in time portray
Pakistan as one of the friendly nations.
So right now Iran is portraying India,
China, Pakistan etc etc etc as friendly
nations. Nations who are not officially
at war with them.
So as long as there is no official
Pakistan involvement in the war against
Iran, they will allow Pakistani tankers
to cross the street of Hormuz. If
Pakistan starts allowing American
military activity on its territory and
its in its airspace, then the Iranians
uh will
uh possibly interdict Pakistani tankers
from crossing the street of hormones
which the Pakistanis could uh you know
could interpret as an act of war
potentially and then things will u
escalate from there. So right now Iran
doesn't want an escalation on the
Pakistani front. That's why they're
allowing them to go. It it makes no big
difference actually right now.
Kakashi says love to where to see love
to see you wear saffron. Thank you sir.
Please explain
2015 NP blockade
and what whether what India did was
correct also kamay is anti-India and
Kashmir but action greater than what's
NP blockade. Let me see what is NP
Nepal. Nepal Nepal blockade. Oh well I
don't have any explanation for that.
I have no explanation for that.
So in 2015, India apparently blockaded
supplies of various things to Nepal
and that led to a significant amount of
anti-India sentiment in Nepal. Before
this blockade, the people of Nepal were
significantly positive towards India
and this blockade soured relations
between the two nations and made the
people of Nepal see India with with
hostility.
Because Nepal was dependent on India for
a lot of supplies of you know oil, gas
whatever groceries, various products and
so on and India imposed a blockade
and that obviously is going to hurt the
sentiments of the people of Nepal who
see us as the same as you know we are
the same people right and that's why
there was a lot of this this gave rise
to a lot of pro-China hedging in Nepal.
that if India is unreliable, let's tilt
towards China. And the Chinese took full
advantage of that, right? It's been more
than 10 years and you can see the result
of that. I don't have any explanation
for this 2015 Nepal blockade.
It did not make any sense from the
strategic or tactical perspective.
It created problems between the two
nations. I simply don't understand the
reason for this blockade.
It was a stupid thing to do is what I
will say. Stupid. Absolutely stupid.
Okay. Kame is anti-India and Kashmir.
The Kame is dead. Iran overall is um
it's anti-India and Kashmir. Verbally.
Verbally. Verbally. They verbally
support whatever nonsense Pakistan does
verbally but they have never taken any
action that is pro Pakistan or
anti-India. What kind of action could be
taken?
Funding
Pakistani terrorists,
supplying Pakistani terrorists, giving
them diplomatic cover. All those things
are done by the Americans.
The Americans for decades in the past
have funded and financed Pakistani
terrorists and terrorist organizations
and they have supplied Pakistan with
indirectly
with weapons and munitions and whatnot
with training and they have repeatedly
given Pakistan diplomatic support and
diplomatic cover
and even now they are taking the side of
Pakistan right even last year during the
three-day war operation The Americans
took Pakistan's side.
Iran has never done any of these things.
They have not given a single rupee or
single whatever to Pakistani terrorists.
They've never sent arms to Pakistani
terrorists. The Iranian support is just
verbal. Verbal support is no support.
Okay? When someone is drowning, you say,
"Oh, I support you. I support you. You
have my full support." Full support sir.
But you don't send put your hand and
pull the person out. Then what what
support is that? That's just verbal
support. Verbal support is no support.
Okay, everyone. I mean, anybody who
uh you're supposed to understand that.
Okay. All right.
P SA says, "Will this war end the US
petro dollar system or Chinese yuan will
rise and all the American vasals will
become Chinese Russian vasals?" Love
from Bhagalpur. Thank you so much, Push
G. Um, will this war end the petro
dollar system? the American petrol
dollar system with the Chinese UN rise
all American missiles will become
Chinese Russian missiles.
See right now we are in a situation
first of all where China and Russia are
not equals. They're not equal nations.
Russia is you could say become slowly
but steadily becoming a de facto Chinese
vasal state.
Okay, it's very heavily dependent on
China.
See, when the war started, the Ukraine
war in 2022,
Russia was in danger of very quickly
becoming a full-fledged Chinese vasal.
And the only thing that saved Russia was
India's decision to start purchasing
huge quantities of Russian oil.
And that gave Russia an alternative
beyond China. It was still dependent on
China for a lot of things, but it also
had a major source of revenue from
India. And India purchased large
quantities of Russian oil for years
until the last half or last quarter of
last year when India started slowing
down its its reducing its its purchase
of Russian oil.
So India saved Russia from becoming a
Chinese vasal
and that um according to the west and
Ukrainians and Americans was India
financing Russia's war against um
Ukraine or whatever right so we bought
Russian oil in very large quantities
Russia was our primary supplier for
years for about 3 years and then last
year we slow started slowing it down
reducing it now we are again purchasing
more
but Russia now is becoming more and more
of a Chinese asset and that is very
dangerous for Russia. So if American
vasals were to become somebody's vasals,
they'll not become Russian vasals.
They'll become Chinese vasile first of
all there is that. Now will this war end
the US petrol system? Well, it depends
on how the war ends. If the war ends
with a stalemate
let's say the war ends tomorrow morning
for whatever reason, then what is the
situation that you will get or at the
end of this war? You will get the
American military bases in the region
are mostly destroyed. Iran is very badly
devastated. Israel is very badly damaged
and the Gulf nations Kuwait, Oman,
Bahrain,
um Qatar, Saudi Arabia, UAE, etc. All
these nations, they have a big question
mark about the about the reliability of
American promises
and they will understand that the US
can't really is not in a position to
help them if Iran attacks again. But
they will also understand that Iran will
not attack them unless America uses
these nations territory to attack Iran.
Um so if the war ends tomorrow morning,
these nations will remain American
vasiles but the vasalhood will be
shakier than before because there will
be no longer be American bases on those
ter on those nations territories
unless the Americans rebuild the bases
which is going to be unacceptable to
Iran.
So I
so then these nations Saudi Arabia,
Kuwait etc. they will now have the
option or they will at least seriously
consider that let's sell oil to China in
yuan not dollars and as because the
Americans don't have bases there anymore
the Americans can't threaten them. See
these American bases were not for
protection they were for occupation
purposes.
Um, so it won't end the US petrol order
system completely, but it will put it on
shaky ground.
But if the Americans and Israelis win
the war against Iran, destroy Iran,
destroy Iran's missile and drone
capabilities
and do a regime change eventually, then
the petro dollar system continues.
So if the war ends in a stalemate, then
the petro dollar system comes on a comes
on shaky ground. Chinese yuan may rise
yes but the US vasals will not become
Chinese or Russian vasals they will
become slightly more somewhat more
independent somewhat more sovereign and
they will not become anyone's vasals
they'll they'll be you know
the amount the extent to which they are
vasalized by the US will will will will
come down so right now if they're 100%
US vasals maybe in the future they'll be
like 30 40% US vasals and they will have
more autonomy. That is what we can
expect. If the war ends in a stalemate,
if the war ends with an Iranian victory,
well, then the situation is very
different. Then the petrol order system
ends or at least is is very badly
damaged,
right? If the Iranians win, if they
defeat the Americans and the Israelis
and the Americans have to completely
withdraw
militarily from West Asia,
then the petrol system is well, it's
half dead, almost dead. The Chinese are
the big winners then.
Yeah. So, it depends whether there's an
Iranian victory, there's a stalemate, or
there's a US victory.
Okay. WBKT says, "Have you ever listened
to the Tuan throat singer Sidash
Mongush?" I have not. I have listened to
other throat singers. I've listened to
Batsurik Vanig. I've listened to the
band called The Who. I'm not aware of
Sidash Mongush. But let's quickly take a
look at who Sidash Mongush is.
Sidash Mongush.
No, no, no, no, no, no. S A I D A S H
Mongush.
Okay. Um, Mongush Tuan for So, he's
Russian from Tua Kazil known for his
throat singing performance. So, I'm
aware of uh of of
B Zorig Zorig Wanchig. Great Mongolian
throat singer. Okay. Very famous guy.
And I am also aware of the who band
uh the who the who they're also awesome.
So their style of music could be could
be called Mongolian folk rock music.
Yeah. Right. Okay.
Anoj art says Q Portugal versus India
getting opportunity in both. What's Q?
Portugal versus India. Getting
opportunity in both. I'm not sure what
that means, but let me see. Q L Portugal
versus India.
What is that? Quality of life.
Portugal versus India. Getting
opportunity in both. Portugal.
Portugal.
Portugal has a way better quality of
life than India. Okay. Go ahead and
follow your dreams. All the best, sir.
Portugal has a far better quality of
life compared to India. There is no
question about that. There's no question
about that. Okay.
Sergeant Skylin says, "Is Pakistan's
military better than Iran's?"
Pakistan's military has only one
advantage. They have nuclear weapons.
But those nuclear weapons are on their
own. They are American nuclear weapons
that are kept on Pakistani territory.
And those weapons are handled by
Americans not by Pakistanis. So if you
remove the nuclear factor, I think Iran
can devastate and destroy Pakistan.
Pakistan has no answer to the kind of
missiles Iran has. Absolutely no answer
whatsoever.
If Iran and Pakistan go to war, it's a
conventional war. Pakistan will be wiped
out. It will be flattened by Iran.
Even if Pakistan tries nukes, Iran will
still win. I think if there's a clash
between Pakistan and Iran, Iran will
devastate and destroy Pakistan
and the infantry capabilities, tanks,
nothing will matter. Iran will flatten
Pakistan from a distance.
And don't ask me about Iran versus
India. Don't ask me that.
Such says, ceasefire. Is the US looking
for an offramp or buying time for a
ground invasion? Will Iran double down
on getting nukes if the war ends in
their favor? Okay, ceasefire. So Trump
had proposed a five-day ceasefire or he
had announced a five-day ceasefire. He
had said that we have been secretly
having conversations with Iran and we
have had very good conversations and we
have decided to have a 5-day ceasefire.
Iran said we have had no conversations.
You're lying. But Trump went ahead and
announced a 5day ceasefire. And what's
happened in the past 5 days? Israel and
the US have struck at Iranian steel
production facilities, the three largest
steel production plants in Iran. They've
destroyed those. They have hit at least
a couple of Iranian nuclear facilities,
civilian nuclear program facilities.
They have destroyed Iranian
universities.
So that's not what a ceasefire looks
like, right? And Iran has obviously
retaliated in various ways. they have
struck uh just now a few few hours ago a
Saudi air base where the Americans had
refueling aircraft and various personnel
and whatnot. So this is not a ceasefire
but Trump's announcement of a ceasefire
was a trick. It was a trap that he laid
for Iran. So the trap was such that
if Trump announces a ceasefire and Iran
says no we don't respect your ceasefire
then Iran looks like the wararmonger the
aggressor. It doesn't really matter what
you look like in a war, but yeah, they
can portray them as the aggressors, as
those who don't want free, don't want
peace. You don't seek peace. I'm giving
you peace, but you don't seek peace. You
are wararmongers. That's what they can
claim.
And if Iran accepts the ceasefire, then
those five days of peace, Trump can use
those five days to reinforce his troops
positions, his military positions in the
region, and bring in more troops to
prepare for ground invasion. It's like
heads you win uh heads I win tails you
lose that sort of thing. Uh but anyway
the is Israelis made sure that there is
no ceasefire and the war has continued.
Uh
Trump is not looking for an offramp.
Trump see if you look at Trump's past
actions.
You will see that he constantly lies.
He lies lies lies. It's a pattern with
him. Right? The US military says that
you know what in a war there is no such
thing as a fair war or just war the only
objective in war is to win
lie cheat do what steal do whatever
matters but win and I think that's how
war is fought today right so you can
trick your enemy and make him look like
a fool if that works great for you um so
the ceasefire was not a ceasefire it's
it's you know there's been constant
fighting and constant attacks and uh the
US doesn't seem to be looking for an
offramp. Trump knows that he is being
humiliated right now and he wants a win.
He wants a win of some kind. So, looks
like the Americans are preparing to
launch a ground invasion of some kind.
Maybe on Karag Island, maybe somewhere
else. Let's take a look at the
geography.
Where is Kar Island? Let's see.
Okay. So, here we have uh the Persian
Gulf region. Okay. And Iran has a number
of islands. The largest one is Kashmir
over here. The Americans in the initial
days of the war hit a desalination plant
on this island. But there is Kha Island
over here. Khark or Kar Island. And if
you look here, there's plenty of uh oil
uh you know there are plenty of oil
reserves etc on this island. Oil oil
storage and transportation facilities on
the island. And the Americans are saying
that, you know, it looks like they want
to invade this island and occupy this
island. A lot of Iran's oil is exported
from this island. Okay. So, it looks
like
the Americans are preparing for a ground
invasion of this island. The question
is, how do you invade this island? If
you want to send a warship through the
Strait of Hormuz to send troops to the
to the island, well, the straight of
Hormos is closed. If you send a warship
in the state of Hormos, it's going to be
destroyed by the Iranians, guaranteed.
So you can't send a warship into the
Persian Gulf. So then how do you do it?
Well, you can maybe send it through
Saudi Arabia. Maybe you can send the
troops through Saudi Arabia. you can
maybe u have the troops transported by
air to a Saudi Arabian airfield air base
and maybe then they can uh you know make
an incursion onto Khark
from one of the Saudi ports maybe that's
what they could do. Uh so there's
multiple options they have maybe from
Kuwait or whatever but all of these
options they sound or look suicidal. So
maybe it's not Karak they want maybe
they may be thinking of perhaps making a
move on Chabahar maybe on Kunarak you
know to catch the Iranians off guard
Chabahar is not far far from Pakistan at
all maybe you can push in troops from
Pakistan into Chavahar
maybe into into you know Kadarak port.
So you have Chabahar and Kodarak which
are ports over here. This is Chabahar
Bay and that could be a target possibly.
So I I don't know but it looks like the
Americans are planning something. I
don't know what they're planning but uh
you see this this ceasefire is merely a
time some 5 days they they've taken
they've set aside to plan for plan for
essentially the next stage of the war.
So I think that's
that's what could happen. I think this
weekend is going to be pretty critical
and we could see the next phase of the
war and maybe more escalations. Yeah. Uh
will Iran double down on getting nukes
if the war ends in their favor? It makes
sense for them to do it. Yes, it makes
sense for them to acquire nuclear
weapons. Of course it makes sense. Team
talks says if the US backs off, will
Israel do the same? They both seem to
have different objectives. The US Senate
is also panicking. Do you think there
can be a coup in the US?
Coup in the US? Well, in the US, a coup
is typically done in a pretty different
way.
In the US, when does a coup happen? A
coup happen when something happens to
the president. That's a coup.
So the last time there was a coup of
that kind was in 1963.
Um the assassination of the American
President John F. Kennedy. That's cool.
And Lyndon B. Johnson took over and he
was very pro deep state. Um Kennedy was
taking on the deep state. So so that's
what happened there. So u Trump is not
against the deep state. He's not
swimming against the current. He's
trying to do his best to, you know,
carry out the instructions of the deep
state. It would look like. So, I don't
see there being a coup in the US unless
Trump messes up catastrophically.
Yeah. Then perhaps it could be. I don't
know what are the avenues to remove a US
president from power. But I'm sure there
are ways and means of doing that. But at
this at this point in time, it doesn't
look like that that sort of thing could
happen. Um, if the US backs off and will
Israel do the same? They seem to have
different objectives. If the US backs
off, Israel is not guaranteed to do do
the same. See, Trump announced a 5day
ceasefire, but Israel kept on hitting uh
Iran, didn't it?
So, Israel won't do what the US says.
But the US seems to be somehow duty
bound to come to Israel's aid no matter
what happens whenever it is required.
So, if the US backs off, Israel will not
do the same. But how long can Israel
keep fighting on its own? Let's say
hypothetically the US backs up and says
we're out. How long can Israel keep
fighting?
That's a big question. Israel can keep
fighting as long as they keep getting
supplies from the US, arms, ammunition,
and so on. If that stops, Israel can't
keep fighting. Israel becomes
defenseless.
So there is that also. But I don't think
Americans will ever stop helping Israel.
So
Kakashi says, "Was Maduro the only
nationalist or patriot in the Venezuelan
government?" I I don't know. I have not
studied um the Venezuelan government's
composition, who are the other people in
the government and how patriotic or not
were they. So I don't know.
I've never really bothered to pay much
attention to Venezuela. I knew about
Maduro, but I did not know about the
other other people in the government.
Right now I know Madame Deli Rodriguez
who is the current leader of Venezuela
who was his number two. I have no idea
who are the others. So I have no idea.
Sorry.
Prutharadana says more S400 is indirect
big no to F-35 speculations.
I think we can now put this F-35
speculation to rest. We are not
acquiring F-35s.
The Iranians took out an F-35.
Okay. And if we are buying more S400,
the Americans can never sell you F35s.
They can't. They simply can't.
Right.
Um, it's their greatest, not it's the
number two best aircraft. The F22 is the
best. The F-35 is the next best
according to them, stealthy aircraft and
so on. But if they sell F-35s to us
hypothetically, but we also have the
Sounded,
then we will know exactly how to take
down an F-35. And since we are now once
again very strongly aligning with Russia
after after signing various agreements
to buy about $25 billion worth of
various things including AR including
arms and rockets and drones, missiles
and whatnot from Russia, nuclear
cooperation as well. Uh the Americans
won't sell us a thing. I'm glad. I'm
glad.
Kakashi says, "Did the US warn India
about 2000 terror attack? If so, why? I
have no idea. I have not studied um you
know the details of the 2008 terror
attack.
I am not aware of the Americans warning
us about it about this at all. I'm aware
that the that the British
were aware of what was happening. they
were actually monitoring the whole
attack in real time somehow
and uh so they were aware of what was
happening. They did not offer any help
despite knowing exactly what was
happening in real time. They did not
offer India any help and the Americans
had an American terrorist involved in
this right David Coleman Headley
and they have never allowed India to
interrogate this guy despite or forget
about extraditing him to India. they
have not allowed India to even
interrogate this guy
despite having an extradition treaty
with India.
So yeah, the the Americans haven't
cooperated in this matter. And there was
an American terrorist who was at the
heart of this matter, right? Who was in
some way at least partially the brains
behind the Pakistani terrorist operation
against India. It was an American
terrorist, David Coleman Headley. The
Americans haven't cooperated with India.
They're hiding something.
There's something to hide.
Okay,
Kakashi says, "Compare dud dur dashan to
Russia today. I don't watch duran. I
last time I watched must have been in
the 1990s or something or early 2000s."
And Russia Today, I don't know much
about them also. So, I don't know what
the comparison could be. I'm not a
regular watcher of either of the two
channels. Russia Today is not even
available on YouTube. I believe they've
been banned from YouTube. They have a TV
channel which I don't quite know how to
watch. because I don't have I have a TV
at I have multiple TVs at home but I
don't watch TV on that I don't have
cable TV or whatever you know so uh no
idea sorry
Indian media talks about Pakistan but
not the northeast the Indian media what
can I say about the Indian media what
can I say about them yeah
matters that are truly important for
India they wake up only after uh the
thing is done right see there was the
time maybe before the year 2020 when for
the entire Indian media
foreign affairs meant Pakistan
Pakistan Pakistan Pakistan I remember
there was a time when Prime Minister
Modi had visited the US he was in the US
and there's a bunch of Indian
senior media people the top ranking
media personel of various Indian media
houses they had gone to the US to cover
the visit of Prime Minister Mr. Modi
Modi to the US and you have these Indian
anchors asking a panel of American
experts but what about Pakistan was
Pakistan discussed Pakistan Pakistan
Pakistan
so for them international affairs and
all that meant only Pakistan
afterwards after Galwan etc suddenly
China appeared China now now there's a
bunch of China experts
okay so now with Pakistan and China the
last few years
people have started focusing on the
focusing on the US and other things as
well trade deals and so on. So now the
media is aware of those things
but the me in India neither the
politicians nor the media have any
understanding whatever whatsoever of the
northeast the far east of India. Nobody
understands that.
Nobody understands
you know the different ethnicities the
ethnic groups the different linguistic
groups in the region what their
histories are what their aspirations are
what the problem what are the problems
they faced each state in the past had
multiple insurgent insurgency movements
what's the history of that what caused
that nobody has any understanding
whatsoever of it everyone sees things
from through a very simplistic lens and
there's tremendous foreign interference
in our far east region
right there's this project K going on
cookie land for for Christ akistan
for Christ akistan for Christ that's
what's going on it's entirely foreign
orchestrated
and there I think only one media channel
was discussing that I went on that
channel right republic I'm glad Arunab
was he discussed this on more than one
occasion uh I don't think anybody apart
from republic they even discussed this
matter.
Uh so yeah there's a lack of
understanding and there's a lack of
interest in in India's northeast
right. Narendra Desh Pande says if tanks
are Bishma remember tanks were named
Bishma drones are Don Achara who are
Karan and Arjun will Duryodan be harmed
before century end
yeah you had tanks named Bishma I don't
know who are Karan and Arjun
uh Karan and Arjun were adversaries
right Karan was the bad guy Karan was a
bad guy he was on the side of the
adheries the the korovas right and he
was not nearly as capable or great as
Arjun.
He was a great friend of Duryodhan.
Uh you know he has he had a tragic
childhood and all. It's okay. Doesn't
mean you to become an admi, right?
There's been plenty of people who had
bad childhoods. It doesn't give you the
the license to become an adheri. Uh so
who are Karan Arjun? I have no idea.
Duryodan be harmed. Who is Duryodhan? Is
it China? Is it Pakistan?
Look, tanks, tanks,
they in today's warfare, in 21st century
warfare, the most important weapons are
drones and missiles today. Okay? Not
even aircraft anymore.
So drones and missiles are going to be
your first second line of offense also
defense.
And then you can have bring in tanks and
aircraft and whatnot.
Uh so that's how I see it. I don't know
what names to give to each but all right
Janya says can you explain types of
missiles in detail ballistic cruise
hypersonic other types maybe okay
let's start with ballistic missiles
ballistic missiles have you studied
Newton's laws of motion have you studied
projectile motion in high school in
projectile motion you have let's say you
throw a stone okay you throw a stone at
a certain angle then that stone will
will the the trajectory it uh will
describe is going to be a parabola. It's
a parabolic arc that the the stone or
the ball or whatever will describe
before it hits the ground again. And
that's the trajectory of your ballistic
missiles. Okay? You launch a ballistic
missile, it goes up into the air, it
exits the atmosphere, it reaches its
high point, and then it comes down in
that parabolic arc. It's it's a standard
projectile motion. Of course, today you
have ballistic missiles that can
maneuver that can launch submunitions
that can that can have maneuverable
re-entry vehicles and whatnot. But your
standard ballistic missile, you know, it
describes the same parabolic arc as a
stone or a ball thrown into the air. Uh
that's a ballistic missile and those
missiles can have different ranges.
short range ballistic missiles which is
maybe 500 km or so maybe 800 km or 1,000
km that's short range there's
medium-range ballistic missiles that are
up to 3,000 km there is intermediate
range ballistic missiles maybe 5,000
6,000 km then there is intercontinental
range ballistic missiles that is I would
say above 8,000 km to 12 15,000 km so
there are different types of ballistic
missiles
And you can use them for different
purposes. You can have different kinds
of warheads, payloads on those missiles,
including nuclear payloads. Um, cruise
missiles are missiles that behave like
aircraft. Okay, they fly like aircraft.
Some of them are subsonic. They'll fly
at the speed of your standard passenger
aircraft, you know, subsonic speeds.
Some of them are supersonic cruise
missiles like the Brahos, which is Mach
2 something. Yeah, that's it flies at
more than two times the speed of sound.
And there's hypersonic cruise missiles
that fly at more than five times the
speed of sound like the siron, the Kjal
etc. Uh and so on. So these are
different types of missiles.
Sarakai says what was mother terrorism
propaganda predict.
What
sakai says what was mother terrorism
propaganda? Predict engine emergency
India.
Mother Teresa propaganda is that the
propaganda is that this woman was a
saint
and she was a great great savior of the
poor.
That's that's the propaganda. Okay.
If you want to understand the truth
behind it, read the book called the
missionary position. Was it Christopher
Hitchens who wrote that? Uh let me see.
Let's quickly take a look at that. The
missionary position. I think it was
Hitchens who wrote that. The missionary
position. Hitchens.
The missionary position. Mother Teresa
in theory and practice. Was it? Yeah.
Read this book if you want to understand
the propaganda around this uh this
individual.
Energy emergency of India. Um
energy emergency of India.
um we could face an energy emergency.
Mr. Modi has kind of hinted about that
in various speeches
um including in parliament. He reminded
us of the days of COVID on more than one
occasion including one occasion when I
was there in the hall.
Um that was a week or so ago in Bharat
Mandapam in Delhi. Uh so look if the
straight of hormones remains closed, if
the straight of Babal Mandib is closed,
if Russia is no longer exo able to
export oil to India, if LG supplies to
India are significantly affected, India
could face an energy emergency in the
coming days. Okay, restaurants could
shut down,
you know, hotels could shut down.
Uh possibly people could, you know, face
shortages of cooking gas and whatnot.
eventually. Okay, so that sort of thing.
Imagine what can go what can go wrong,
what what more can happen. So yeah,
that's a possibility. Hopefully it
doesn't happen, but we have to be
prepared mentally for this and the
government will have to prepare um you
know contingency measures for this.
Rumit Mishra says since Pakistan is a US
is it possible for the US to start a
ground invasion from Pakistan as it
shares a border with Iran? It is
certainly possible
uh the Americans may launch possibly.
Looks like they're preparing for some
kind of ground invasion of Iran. Okay.
So let's once again discuss that. Once
again let's go to the map. Okay.
So this is the map of the region. This
is Iran squarely in the in the center of
the screen. Right.
Now there's a possibility that's been
discussed that the Americans want want
to take this island Kirk Island.
But it's very well defended and it's not
far away from the Iranian u you know sea
coast. Uh what's the distance? Let's say
it's about 30ish kilometers 30 35 km
from the Iranian coast. Which means that
if the Americans even succeed, even if
they succeed in taking the island, they
will be they will have to take the brunt
of Iranian um missile fire and it's very
very hard for you to survive that
right and even if you can take the
island, you can survive the Iranian
missile attacks, how will you be
resupplied? You need food, water. You
when you invade, you take a couple of
days worth of food and water. After
that, what happens? So, it's very
difficult to take that island. But you
know what? What if the Americans want to
invade Chabahar and take Chabahar?
Chabahar or even uh Konarak. So that's
not very far away from the Pakistani
border. What's the distance between
Chabahar and the Pakistan border? Let's
say the Balojasthan region. It's about
100 kilometers. So this may be more
likely. Maybe the Americans launch an
invasion from Guadada
or something like that. So that's also a
possibility. So it is certainly possible
that that the Americans may launch a
surprise invasion of Iran from Pakistani
territory. Very very possible. Yeah.
Because as you know Pakistan is a
full-fledged American wasal. It is
Shatabish says bit off topic.
Objectivity is disappearing from every
form of life personal social media news
education decision-m
on almost every level. Is it fair to say
this is a reliable trait of kal rel
relatable trait of kalyuga?
Objectivity is disappearing from every
form of life. Um the media media is full
of propaganda. I would agree with that.
Social media is full of propaganda.
News the news media is full of
propaganda. Yes. Education at least in
India is full of propaganda and and
distortions
and poor quality teaching. uh personal
life and decision-m well it depends on
you whether the objectivity is
disappearing from your personal life you
know that's a personal choice uh
decision- making no objectivity I'm not
sure about that it depends on where you
are in some nations you have objectivity
some some nations you have less
objectivity but overall you're seeing
more of this happening I would agree
that overall seeing more and more of
propaganda and distortions all over the
place yes is this a trait of Khal
Kalyuga. I'm not sure what has been
written about Kalyuga. What are the
characteristics of Kali Yuga, but yeah,
it looks like this this is a signature
trait of Kali Yuga. Lies, chaos,
misrepresentation, propaganda,
the victory of Dharma or Dharma, the
victory of Asatya or Satya. Yeah, these
are traits of Kalyuga indeed.
Akit Sharma says Iranian missiles. Thank
you people of India, your views. I'm not
sure if this is true news or fake news.
I've seen some reports on social media
on some social media accounts
claiming that Iranians Iranians Iranian
missiles have been inscribed with with
the the statement thank you the people
of India. I'm not sure if it's true or
false. It could be propaganda. I don't
know.
So I'm not sure if it is reliable
information. Anybody can Photoshop or an
image of a missile and put some such
words on that or you could use AI for
that. How will you know the difference?
I mean, I'm sure there are ways of
finding out if an image has been
manipulated. But for the for the 99.9%
of people who don't know how to do it,
it will look like the truth. So, I don't
know if it's reliable information or
not. So, that's why I will desist from
commenting.
Praep Kumar says your insights offer
great clarity. Great fine. Thank you.
Thank you very much. Trump extended
sessation of hostilities hostilities
till the 7th of April. Is he buying time
for a land invasion? Your take? Okay.
Has he extended the secession of
hostilities? Let's find out.
Has Trump extended the ceasefire until
the 7th of April?
has he?
Yes. Based on reports from March 26, 27,
Donald Trump announced an extension of
the pause on striking Iran's energy
infrastructure by 10 days, setting a new
deadline of April 6 Eastern time, which
is April 7 in some time time zones.
Uh he's pausing the destruction of
Iranian power plants and energy
infrastructure to allow ongoing
negotiations to proceed.
per Iran government request.
Um it's uh the extension is intended to
allow Iran to open the straight of
Hormos and address a US backed proposal
aimed at ending the war. Trump is saying
that talks are going very well. Iranian
officials have dismissed the US proposal
as one-sided and unfair and they have
publicly denied that direct negotiations
are taking place. The previous deadline
was for March 26.
So Trump has announced an extension of
the so-called pause,
but it's only a pause on striking Iran's
energy infrastructure. So he has said
that we we're going to pause striking
Iran's energy infrastructure. But that
means you can still continue striking
Iranian um steel plants, Iranian um
universities, Iranian airports, whatever
else. Thran. So that I suppose will
continue. Well, that's hardly a
ceasefire.
That's hardly a ceasefire. Uh but why is
he doing that? So, first of all, he's
claiming that the Iranians are
negotiating with him, which the Iranians
are denying. They're saying it's a lie.
He's lying.
Um so, clearly, it's it's uh he's trying
to buy time for some kind of uh for
regrouping
and maybe launch an invasion, right?
But as long as Israel keeps striking
striking at Iran, Iran will not stop
striking back at American assets and
bases in the region. I suppose by now
the American bases must be completely
destroyed if not very severely severely
degraded. I think that is very clear by
now. Um
so what is American action right now in
the region? I really wonder are the
Americans still launching some kind of
strikes on Iran or is it only Israel
who's doing that?
Um so I I think this war will go on
if Trump has said that we will no longer
strike at Iran's energy infrastructure
until um 7th of April but Israel keeps
striking at other infrastructure etc.
then it makes no difference from Iran's
perspective, right? So I suppose the war
will go on but maybe the Americans will
be able to regroup because they are
right now not involved in the action
directly. So they can regroup,
strategize, plan and then proceed with
the next phase of the war. So I don't
think it's going to lead to any I think
it's unlikely
to lead to an actual end to this war. I
think the Americans are simply trying to
buy time for the next phase of whatever
they're planning to do.
Kakashi says in UN vote to condemn
slavery only US, Israel and Argentina
voted against the European Union
abstained. Mille went to the wailing
wall and says he's the most Zionist
president in the world.
Okay, that's interesting. UN vote to
condemn slavery. Let's let's uh double
let's let's double check that.
Which nations abstained in the recent UN
vote to condemn slavery?
52 nations abstained including all 27
members of the EU. The UK abstained,
Canada, Australia and Japan abstained.
Okay. USA, Israel and Argentina voted
against it.
So the resolution was to label the
transatlantic slave trade as the gravest
crime against humanity and supporting
reparations.
So the resolution passed but the US,
Israel and Argentina voted against this.
So the US, Israel and Argentina do not
consider the transatlantic slave trade
as the gravest crime against humanity.
Um okay. What was India's position? I
wonder
what was India's position. Let's ask the
Google AI.
Uh, of course, you should remember the
AI is not always necessarily telling you
the truth. But let's see
how did India vote in this resolution.
India, what did India what was India's
position?
India abstained from the resolution.
Okay. India abstained.
I
Okay. So, India abstained,
the EU abstained, Japan abstained,
um
UK abstained.
Okay. And India abstained.
But the US, Israel and Argentina voted
against.
So they don't consider this to be the
gravest crime against humanity.
If you had asked me
to decide on India's behalf, I would
have abstained.
Now, why would I have abstained? Let me
tell you why. The transatlantic slave
trade,
uh, how many people were trafficked as a
consequence of this? Maybe 10 million,
maybe 20 million, let's say 50 million.
Let's, let's ask Google Google's AI.
Let's let's see what it has to say.
How many people are estimated to have
been trafficked in total as a
consequence of the transatlantic slave
trade?
Let's see what the numbers are.
10 to 15 million Africans.
Okay. 10 to 15 million Africans.
Is this the gravest crime against
humanity? It is not.
It is not the gravest crime against
humanity. When the Europeans
colonized, very nice word, colonized.
When the Europeans colonized the
Americas, about a 100 million natives
were killed as a consequence,
the transatlantic slave trade pales into
insignificance compared to the genocide
perpetrated on the native Americans by
the Europeans.
So, the US is correct. It's not the
gravest crime against humanity.
The US is a nation that that was founded
on genocide
then slavery.
Genocide came first and in the US the
continental US I wonder at least half of
that must have happened or a third of
that maybe 33 million deaths would have
happened there perhaps. I don't know
what the numbers are, right? But so the
genocide of the Native Americans, it
consumed about 100 million lives. Even
that's not the greatest genocide of all.
The worst genocide ever perpetrated in
human history
was perpetrated by the Turks against
Indians.
over a period of about 700 800 years
approximately 500 million Indians would
have died.
Okay. So 700 to 800 million 700 to 800
years. Let's say it's 700 years and 500
million Indians. So that's less than a
million a year when you have a
subcontinent with a population of 330 or
so million.
If a million die million people die per
year, less than a million die per year,
that's less than 0.3%.
And that continues for 700 years, you
have more than 500 million deaths.
That was the worst genocide ever. It
happened against us. So if you had asked
me to to vote, I would have abstained.
Uh,
okay. About MLE, I I have no comments
about what MLE said.
Krishant Boralo says, "Have you watched
Durand thus far?" No, I haven't watched
it yet. I I'm trying to find the
earliest possible slot where I can watch
it. It's a 4-hour movie, so I'm going to
have to set aside a big chunk of time.
This coming week, I will definitely
watch it. Yeah.
Ritiki says, "What's happen? What's
going on between Russia and Ukraine in
the war? Is it a stalemate or has or has
Russia captured more territory despite
Ukraine hitting their oil sites?" I
wonder what is happening. So, what's
happened in the past few days is that
the Ukrainians have blown up about 50
40% of Russia's um oil export
capabilities, right? Let's let's see
once again what did we have?
Um
where was this?
Okay. Uh so once again, let's go back.
Let me put this on the screen.
So, what's happening is is really
perplexing.
This is from March 23.
Massive Ukrainian drone strikes blew up
vast areas of the port of Pilmore,
Russia's largest oil export terminal
that processes about 100 million tons of
oil and oil products per year. Then you
have a major Ukrainian drone strike hit
Russia's Luga port. Okay, massive
attack.
So 40% of Russia's oil exports are
currently stopped after Ukraine attacked
the Primorskuga
and Novo Rossk Novo Rosisk crude oil
ports. So the Nova Rosisk port is in uh
the Black Sea and Primorsk and Usluga
are up north right and this is this is
major major uh attack on Russia. 40% of
Russia's oil exports are currently
stopped. And this is continuing. This is
continuing. This is this is like from a
couple of days ago. This is from
yesterday.
They're trying to completely destroy
Russia's oil production and
transportation capabilities
and Russia's oil exports. So, Russia,
Ukraine is going hammer and tongs after
Russia
and Russia is sitting and taking it. I'm
sure they're responding in some way, but
it's
Russia looks rather helpless right now.
Right. So, Russia has captured
territory. Sure. Maybe a fifth of what
used to be the nation of Ukraine. They
have taken the Donbas region, the Lhas,
the Luhans, Donetsklasts and so on so
forth, right? About a fifth or to a
fourth of Ukraine's earthwile territory,
also Crimea.
But after that, it's been a war of
attrition. It's been a frozen conflict,
long war.
And it made sense that Russia weaponizes
time and all that to drain Europe. Who
are their who are their enemies? I
understand that. But right now, Russia
is sitting and taking it more or less.
They may have launched a thousand more
drones at Ukraine in response to this.
But has it done the kind of damage to
Ukraine that the Ukrainians have done to
Russia?
So, I don't know what's going on. What
is going on in Putin's mind?
Has Russia been offered some kind of
ceasefire proposal
from the US and Russia is just waiting
for something to happen
or is Russia now just sitting and taking
it? So I'm not sure what's happening.
Ukraine seems to becoming be becoming
more and more capable and Russia seems
to be right now it looks a little
helpless
and we know that Russia has tremendous
military capabilities but Russia's
sitting back right now which is
perplexing. There is something going on
behind the scenes that I am not aware
of. Right?
So there is some information that I
lack. That information could explain
Russia's behavior
because Russia has all the options on
the table that against Ukraine that
Donald Trump has against Iran. Trump and
is Israel together have hit Iran's
industrial sites, steel production
sites, desalination plants, oil
production sites and oil reservoirs, oil
storage sites. They have hit uh Iran's
universities, schools, they've
assassinated Iran's supreme leader. I
think Putin has all those options on his
table also, but for some reason he's not
exercising any of them. I'm not saying
he should or he should not. I'm just
making an observation here. I'm not
recommending he should do this or that.
None of my business. I'm a neutral
observer.
But he has the same options on his table
that Trump has. He also has those
capabilities. But Putin, for some
reason, has chosen thus far not to
exercise any of those.
I'm not saying he should do this or
that, but the lack of u
response
to what Ukraine is doing is a little or
more than a little perplexing. So, I'm
not sure what's going on.
Call Mitrids says, "Why does the US give
so much importance to tiny Israel
history?" I don't have an answer to this
question. Um I mean, I could answer this
question. I mean the answer obviously is
a plausible answer that you know a lot
of very prominent American politicians
are of Jewish
uh ethnicity origin whatever it is right
so a lot of Jewish people occupy very
prominent positions in the US government
and in US politics
and the Jewish community is always
pro-Israel and they are a very
tight-knit uni unified community there's
a lot of unity among the Jews, right?
And because of that, it makes sense
that, you know, America's position has
always been pro-Israel. The Jews have
been very prominent and very very
powerful and very uh influential in the
US for uh way more than a century. Way
more than than a century.
In the 19th century, there was there was
a time when Jews were uh demonized and
they were despised by various American
politicians. But for the last
century and a quarter at least, the Jews
have been very influential.
Um, you know, there was a time when
about almost 30% of New York citizens
were Jews. You know, uh, when was that?
Let's let's let's find out, shall we?
Let's see. What was the Jewish
population of New York in the 1920s?
see 29% of the city's population.
By 1920, Jews were about 29% of New York
City's total population, the largest
Jewish city in the world. And New York
is obviously America's financial center.
So that kind of tells you how important
and how powerful and how influential
Jewish people are in America's
industries, in America's uh economy and
of course in American politics. So when
you are very influential in these
sectors,
energy, industry,
finance and politics,
well
that explains why the US is always so
incredibly pro-Israel.
Menuk says Menuk, US Ukraine citizens
who went to Mizuam posed no threat to
India.
Why this stand? Why are we not calling
the Yankees out? Why are cookies so
important to us?
Okay. When you say Sha, who is it? Is it
the Sha of Iran?
Which Sha is this?
Are you talking about are you talking
about the Indian home minister Mr. Amit
Shra? Uh let's ask Google has m whether
Mr. Sha has made any statements.
Has India's home minister Mr. Amit Sha
made any statements about the American
and Ukrainian citizens who were arrested
recently?
He stated Mr. Amit Sha India's home
minister Mr. Amitra stated that a group
of foreigners including one American and
six Ukrainians arrested in the NI
arrested by the NIA in Mizoram posed no
threat to India. The arrests were
related to alleged violations of the
restricted areas act and the ind
individuals were taken into custody.
They were not perceived according to Mr.
Sha as a danger to the country.
Uh okay.
So I was not aware of this and it's an
interesting statement. See,
arresting a bunch of Ukrainians is no
big deal, but arresting an American is a
big deal because the US is the most
powerful and dangerous country in the
world. And uh look, they have a big
issue if uh something happens to one of
the citizens.
In the US, their citizens die of drugs
or whatever, they don't care. But
outside of the US, it's a prestige
issue. Um
now, what does that have to do with
this? possibly something possibly
nothing.
Uh so I'm not sure what the deal is.
This is the first time I'm hearing about
this that Mr. Amit said that they did
not pose any threat to India.
Maybe it's just a diplomatic statement.
You know, words versus actions. Verbally
you say that it is no big deal. They did
not pose any threat to India. But
legally you take action against them as
if they are posing a threat to India.
That's one possibility. I'm not sure. So
I'm not sure why the stand why this
stand has been taken. Maybe it is just
words. Like I say, ignore words and look
at actions.
So, ignore the words, ignore the
statements, just observe the actions.
What actual actions is the government of
India taking against these individuals?
The time will tell. The next few days
will tell. Will they be kept in judicial
custody? Will they be released on bail
and escape from India? If they are kept
in judicial custody, if they're charged
with some crimes, what crimes are they
be charged? Are they being charged
charged under? And so on. We have to see
about that. Uh why why are we not
calling Yankees out? Because the Yankees
are very dangerous. That's why we are
not calling them out. Okay. Very
dangerous. Very dangerous. Why are
cookies so important to us? Well, that's
a question you have to ask to the
government of India.
Why are the cookies so important to us?
That's a question you have to ask to the
government of India.
I am not the right person to answer this
question.
Right angle says we convert our
agricultural production to fuel. We do
not need to import gas. Why our leader
not looking for energy drive economy? We
can convert plastic to diesel.
It's saying yeah this this is this is
true right?
Uh you can convert biomass biomass into
into fuel.
You can uh
see every household
produces waste.
When you chop vegetables, you peel them
off and there's a lot of uh waste
product that is produced, right?
So that's one form of u organic waste
that can be turned into fuel. Then every
human being has to poop. That can be
turned into fuel. Right? So if we uh
harness all these uh waste products that
come out of every household
and if you
harness that and you turn that into
whether it is uh bio gas or various
kinds of fuel
and if you can do that effectively and
at scale then you don't really need to
import
at least gas Right.
So that and I don't know about
converting plastic to diesel. Is it is
it is it possible? Can you convert
plastic to diesel? Can plastic be
converted to diesel?
Yes, it can be converted into diesel and
other fuel oils through a process called
pyrolysis which involves heating waste
plastic in an oxygen free environment to
break down its molecular bonds. This
converts solid plastic into gas which is
then condensed into liquid creating a
fuel that can power diesel engines often
blended with conventional diesel. So
once again India produces a lot of
plastic waste. This can also be
converted into diesel. But the problem
is how do we harvest the waste products
of each household? How do we effectively
segregate all the plastic from other
waste and then properly channel it into
these these factories or whatever these
plants where it can be converted into
diesel. You will have to set up a whole
new infrastructure for doing this. India
is a super inefficient and super
allegedly corrupt country where nothing
is done efficiently.
So theoretically we have everything we
need to produce lot of diesel and to
produce all the bio gas we need but to
create that infrastructure
and to
make this happen at scale it's it's
going to take a lot of logistical effort
and because of the inefficiencies in in
alleged corruption in India it's almost
impossible for this to happen. It can
happen I would say it should happen.
It's a great opportunity for India,
right? But it will take logistic
logistics. It will take engineering.
It will take proper leadership and
governance and administration. It can be
made to happen in the next 3 to 5 years.
Maybe sooner, maybe two years it can be
done. In a nation like China, it can
happen in 6 months. I suppose 6 months
to one year, maybe two years. So, it
certainly can happen. uh why our leader
not looking for energy drive economy
look I don't know why our leader is not
doing this or not doing that that only
the leader can answer but yes this
certainly is a great opportunity
to to create to to to convert a problem
into a great solution a long-term
long-lasting solution it's a great
opportunity let's see what uh our
leadership does about this
rtx army says Iran blast trusts a
Pakistani tanker in Hormuz for helping
the US. Fascinating. Let's see.
Did Iran target a Pakistani oil tanker
in the state of Hormuz?
Okay. Reports that Iran destroyed a
Pakistani oil tanker in the state of
Hormuz are currently unverified and
appear to be part of a viral false claim
circulating on social media. Okay. So, I
don't know if it's true or not. Right
now the the AI is telling me that it
it's unverified. So okay we'll we'll
wait and watch.
Vijay
Bupat
Langawan says love your insights on
geopolitics Jind. Thank you so much
Vijay G. Thank you so much Jind. Thank
you.
Right angle says why government sponsor
traitor like
like air amir shahuk khan look
I think this question should be asked to
the government not to me I don't know I
don't speak on behalf of the government
I don't represent the government of
India I don't know the thought process
and
traitor that um I don't know so look I'm
not the person to the right person to to
answer this question. Okay.
Saksham says, "Thoughts on us on
thoughts on India said we are not dal
like Pakistan." Good. Very nice laser
statement. Very nice. Very good.
What job? Excellent.
Right. Angle says all IPL team buying
Pakistani player in other leagues. Why?
Because it's legal to buy Pakistani
players in other other leagues. It's
banned in India. In other countries, if
you have your franchise team there, you
can legally buy Pakistani players
because the government of India has not
imposed any restrictions on what IPL
teams can do outside of the country.
That's why because it is not illegal.
They are doing it.
It's not illegal. Is it right? I would
not say it's right. I think it's not
right. But because it's not illegal,
they're doing it. If the government of
India issues a clear directive not to do
it, I suppose they'll have to stop
because they are Indian teams. But
because there is no such direction from
the government, they're doing it. I
think that's terrible.
Sanchar Chilikuri says, "Us purpose of
this war? Is it depriving China of
energy and dent their AI race in
sustenance?
Um
the US purpose. Why did the US start
this war? See, yeah, it has something to
do with China for sure. Absolutely. See,
this year it began rather ominously with
the US regime change operation in
Venezuela. They walked into Venezuela
into Karakas and they killed a bunch of
people there and they captured the
president of Venezuela, Mr. Maduro, and
they took him hostage. Right. They
kidnapped him and they took him to the
US and they did a regime change
essentially de facto regime change in
Venezuela which means that they made
they ensure that the the government that
is now in power is very pliable which it
is it does what the Americans say and
that's how the Americans have taken
control of the Venezuelan energy
reserves.
So that's a that's a small setback for
China. Not a huge one but small but
still it's there and now they have gone
after Iran and the objective see Trump
thought that the Americans are were
going to win the war in a couple of days
okay that's what he had expected the
objective was to do a regime change in
in Iran and then to take control of
Iran's oil reserves
control that and that's how they would
be able to deprive China of about 20% 15
to 20% of its oil supply which would be
a big big massive blow to era. So that
was the objective.
The objective of the US was to take
control of all the oil producing nations
in the world. Taking control as in
either taking over directly or
vasalizing them, converting turning them
into vasals.
Uh that's not worked out obviously. So
one of the objectives was that the
second objective was to uh help Israel
once again. So, so the American
objective was to uh take control of the
oil. Israel's objective was a regime
change and America also wanted that. Um
yeah, essentially that
Dhad says Trump is anti-West. I think
the deep state wants the West to fall.
Trump is anti-West.
What is the West?
First, let's address that question.
What's the west? The west is the US and
its western European vasals. That is the
EU and NATO nations. That's the west.
Also, politically, Australia and South
Korea and Japan are politically part of
the West. Even though they are
geographically not part of the West, but
politically they're part of the West.
So, it's the US, it's Canada,
it's the EU and NATO nations, it's
Japan, South Korea, and Australia.
That's the West.
Politically, Mexico etc. are not part of
the west. Okay? They are the global
south. Argentina, Brazil, Mexico, they
are politically part of the global
south, not part of the west. So now, now
that we understand what the west is, is
Trump anti-West? Is Trump anti- Canada?
Is he anti-EU? Is he anti-NATO? Is he
anti-Japan, South Korea, Australia? not
so much as being anti- them as being uh
very rude and dismissive of them.
So in the past
um the US before Trump also these
nations were American was but they were
treated as equals at least in public
behind the scenes whatever happened
happened okay but in public they were
treated with respect they were treated
as equals of the G7 and all whatever
right that sort of thing so they were
treated as equals but now they are being
humiliated by Trump in public
you know that that illusion
of of of uh courtesy, politeness of
civil of civilized behavior, all of that
has been destroyed.
So, and and Trump has been taking
actions that are so forget about the
illusion and all the behavioral things
and all, but u even when it comes to
actions, Trump has been very harsh
towards his uh his vasals. He impose all
kinds of punitive sanctions, punitive
tariffs on them. Do we still remember
the tariff war? all those heavy tariffs
that were imposed on them, he forced the
EU, the NATO nations to to essentially
double their contribution, their
financial contribution to NATO by 2030.
So the NATO nations have accepted
everything Trump said. So they have been
humiliated over and over again. They
have been arm twisted and that sort of
thing. And now
you know there are nations who have
purchased American weapons, who have
placed orders for American weapons that
the Americans are not going to deliver
now. and they have misappropriated those
funds for their own benefit. So the
Americans are now essentially
outright stealing
money from their vasals. So
and and
the past few years the Americans have
been de-industrializing Europe. It was
Biden who blew up the Nordstream 2
pipeline which was delivering very large
quantities of very cheap gas to the EU
nations to the European economy. Without
that the European nations went into
like Germany etc. they went into a
recession.
So it's not just Trump who is doing
this. It's the US overall that's doing
it. Okay.
Various at least two American presidents
have been doing this. Now assuming all
American presidents are controlled by
the deep state, looks like the deep
state wants to
well they want to transform the world.
Um they want a very openly overtly
imperial system now.
Um they want a different kind of world
order, the so-called rules-based world
order. It has it no longer serves their
interests. That sort of thing. So uh
they want the US and Israel to succeed
and other nations fail at their expense.
That sort of thing seems to be going on.
Dir Khad says Israel wants to be the
second superpower.
Possible. Yeah, it's possible. Looks
like they want to expand their their
territorial uh extent and become the
only power in West Asia.
Um and they of course are a nuclear
power. So, and they have they they have
very good relations, very good terms
with the US. So, you could say that they
could be in the process of aspiring to
be the second superpower. Yeah.
Iden Trestler says, "Is stopping a war
hard? If so, did India did great with
Operation Synindur?"
Um,
is stopping a war hard?
If you have two reasonably evenly
matched adversaries
and neither of them has achieved what
they seek in a war
and both have lost more than they had
bargained for, then it becomes really
hard to stop a war. It becomes really
hard. But if you have a pos situation
where you have
an unequal contest where one nation one
belligerent is obviously more powerful
than the second one then the more
powerful one can end the war on their
terms.
So in the case of US versus Iran, the US
is way more powerful.
But locally, regionally, Iran has been
more than a match for them and Israel
put together.
The US has only one way of fighting war,
the bulldozer method, brute force
method, but it's not working against
Iran. And Iran has been they've done
their homework really well. And Iran has
essentially thus far lost the war
tactically but strategically they they
have been winning since day one.
And uh
for Trump it's a matter of his ego right
we will be humiliated if he does not
achieve uh clear clearly a clear victory
or or the objectives he had started the
war for. So for him it's very difficult
to end the war.
for Iran. Well, if the war ends
tomorrow, it's going to be a victory, a
strategic victory for them. Uh when it
comes to India and Oprah Synindur,
well, it is a good perhaps a good thing
that India ended the war after three and
a half days or whatever. But uh
who won that war, the three-day war
against Pakistan?
See, India did not achieve achieve any
India did not acquire any territory.
So what was the outcome of the war? It
was like a slap in the face for
Pakistan.
Okay, India won the military victory.
India destroyed a whole bunch of
terrorist training camps, killed a whole
bunch of terrorists, destroyed a whole
bunch of Pakistani uh military
facilities, air force facilities and so
on. Pakistanis could not hit a single
land a single blow on India. But the
Pakistanis won the narrative war because
of Trump's support that they destroyed.
I don't know what starting with three,
four, five, six, seven Indian Indian
aircraft that sort of thing. Trump kept
on repeating. So the Pakistanis won the
narrative war for a while. Now it's not
the case but initially they won the
narrative war. But on a on the military
front, India obviously hit Pakistan very
hard and I think Trump made India stop.
So I don't know what the actual military
objectives were
for India. Did we only want to give them
a slap in the face or did we actually
want to acquire some territory or regain
some territory?
you a war is not won through a sports
score line you know 70 or 181 or
whatever a war is decisive decisively
won when there's an exchange of
territory so that India did not achieve
but overall yeah India stopped the war
after 3 days maybe it was a good thing
maybe perhaps
Amisha G good evening ma'am the
situation in India is not good because
of the war the situation in India is
It's difficult right now. You're right.
It's difficult. India is facing a
shortage of well I'm not sure if it's an
official shortage or not but uh there is
growing anxiety about the supply of uh
cooking gas whether it is LPG, LNG
whatever. Um some one hears some
restaurants may be may already be in the
process of being affected. Um if the
straight of hormones remains closed and
there's the shortage of oil coming into
India from Russia because 40% of
Russia's oil exports have been hit now
then there's going to be a long-term
problem for India that could very badly
affect India's economy right it could
India it could affect India's households
if there is a shortage of cooking gas in
the future so the situation is not good
and who's responsible for this disaster
It is Trump and Israel who are
responsible for this for starting this
war
and if they started a war they should
have ensured it would have that it
should have ended fast but it's just
escalating now escalating escalating
escalating
so it doesn't look that this war is
ending anytime soon and soon it it is
possible that the straight of Babala
Mandib may also be closed
so yeah you are right the situation is
not good right now I hope the Government
of India is planning
and and putting in place contingency
measures of various kinds
uh to ensure that India is not hit too
hard by the by the continuation of this
war.
Ready always ready says India Iran
versus India at present please
okay Iran versus India Iran doesn't have
nuclear weapons India has that's number
one India has a much bigger navy than
Iran
much larger much more capable navy than
Iran India has a much larger air force
than Iran
Iran most likely has way more drones and
possibly better drones than India.
India, Iran definitely has way more
missiles, ballistic missiles, way more
ballistic missiles than India.
Cruise missiles, not sure about how many
cruise missiles Iran has.
India may have a few thousand cruise
missiles, Brahmos type missiles, which
are very very dangerous.
Um, yeah. So that's the kind of
comparison one could make. But in
today's context, so I don't know how
many tanks Iran has. India has lots of
tanks.
But in today's context, it is missiles
and drones that make all the difference.
And I I think Iran is way ahead of India
in terms of drones and missiles. That's
a very brief comparison between the two.
Crack easily. Thank you very much.
Krakisily
Krakisily says, "What's your view on
CAPF bill for India internal security
impact?" I am not aware of this bill but
let's take a look at what it could be.
CAPF bill India.
What is that? Cap bill. Central Armed
Police Forces Kap
bar and bench. Let's see what it is. The
bill empowers the central government to
frame service rules by notification.
Overriding code judgments in existing
laws.
Overriding court judgments in existing
Okay. I have no idea what this bill is.
What is cap in India?
A central armed police forces.
Okay.
NDTV. What does it have to say? The bill
seeks to create a unified legal
framework for governing personnel across
different cap forces.
Okay, look, I have not studied this
bill. I'm sure there's a lot of legal
stuff in that. I I don't know. So, I
don't have any views about this right
now. And I typically don't look into
things that are internal matter. I look
at geopolitics. I look at history. I
look at science. I don't look at bills
that pass in India. So, it's it's beyond
my purview unfortunately. Okay.
Right. Angle says, "Can submarine cut
fiber cable? If yes, impact on India.
I suppose submarines could do it."
Yeah,
I'm sure submarines can do it. You're
talking about internet cables. Internet
cables that you know fiber. Yeah. Impact
on India. I have not studied it, but
it's possible it could have a massive
impact on India's internet. Uh
a lot of these uh internet cables pass
through the straight of hormones, right?
Let's see.
Do internet fiber cables pass through
the straight of hormones.
Let's see.
Yes, critical subc fiber optic cables
pass directly through the state of
hormones serving as a vital digital
outreting the Middle East, Europe, and
Asia.
These cables are essential for internet
connectivity for Gulf nations, UAE,
Qatar, etc. and carry significant
internet traffic for India. Oh,
that could be a big problem for India if
something happens to those.
So, it's also a digital choke point. The
straight of Hormuz.
What's the impact on India if if some of
these f some of these cables are cut?
Let's see.
um
it would significantly impact India's
digital economy as this corridor handles
about a third of India's westward data
traffic.
So rerouting traffic through longer
paths while the Pacific would increase
long roundtrip latency from 80 millconds
to over 200 millconds causing
catastrophic slowdowns for real-time
applications like video calls and
gaming.
Okay, long story short, yeah, it will
have a big big impact and a very bad
impact on India's digital economy and
India's internet connectivity
and that's bad.
Danush has become a new member. Thank
you very much, Danush. Welcome to the
channel's membership. Thank you.
Ritik Yadwanchi says, "Why can't Russia
defend its oil ports from deep from deep
Ukraine strikes when those same strikes
were sites were targeted before?
Shouldn't air defense be stronger there?
That's a big question. That's a that's
very perplexing, right? Why is Russia
not able to defend its uh its ports um
which account for so much of its of
Russia's oil exports?
Um
I think it's very very difficult in
today's day and age to defend critical
infrastructure and installations from
from drones.
You know, drone warfare is evolving very
rapidly and there's measures and counter
measures being that are being taken in
real time,
drone offense and anti- drone defense.
But if you send, let's say, a thousand
drones, a swarm of thousand or 2,000
drones,
first of all, they don't turn, they
don't show up on radar if they are
low-flying drones and they are anywhere
small, right?
And if they have a long range, thousand
kilometers or whatever, then you can
send a thousand drones, 2,000 drones to
one place and then just bombard the
place
without any warning. Then how do you
defend against that? There's no anti-
drone missiles.
I mean, you can use missiles for that,
but that's stupid. As you can see, as
we've seen in the the in the Iran war,
taking down a $1,000 drone or $10,000
drone with a $3 million missile makes no
sense. And if there's a thousand drones
coming in, 2,000 of them coming in, how
many? You won't have those many
missiles. You could use
shotguns, but shotguns aren't that
accurate.
um you could use the kind of
um anti- drone measures India used
during operation but Russia doesn't seem
to have learned that lesson. So I don't
know what Russia is doing and I'm not
sure why Russia is not retaliating
against Ukraine after these terrible
terribly effective strikes. I'm not
sure. Uh yeah so I would say that yes
Russia's air defense should be stronger
but I'm not sure what's going on.
Is it that hard to defend certain ports?
I'm not sure.
Perplexing. Russia should have taken
better measures.
Yeah. After all, we've seen what Ukraine
was able to do last year in Operation
Spider when they sent drones uh and
destroyed
significant numbers of Russian strategic
bombers deep inside Russia. Russia
should have learned the lesson of the of
of from operation spider web, right? and
they should have identified critical u
locations that needed to be defended
against future strikes like those but it
looks like Russia hasn't learned those
lessons which is very strange.
Noise says Nepales are Nepales are
Biharis but with superiority complex.
Okay sir I am not aware of that but okay
thank you for sharing your opinion sir.
Abishek says coid9 new variant BA32 your
views what
really really
oh please oh enough of COVID
I think we need to move past COVID now
new variance whatever uh what's my views
nothing no views about this
Nishan Johan says you said don't ask
about India was I gave my gave my
opinion. You said don't ask about India
versus Iran but I want to hear your
opinion maybe in wargaming manner. I
think India needs to learn much too much
from this current GCC war. Love your
work sir. Thank you so much. So like I
said in terms of nuclear cap
capabilities India is Iran doesn't have
any. India has nuclear capabilities in
terms of air force. India has a way
better air force in terms of naval naval
capabilities. India has way better naval
capabilities in terms of its infantry.
India's infantry, you know, ground
military is way more well larger in
number than Iran. India has way more
tanks than Iran. But in terms of drones
and missiles, Iran most likely has way
more drones than India. And Iran most
likely has way more ballistic missiles
than India. Way more. India may possibly
have more cruise missiles. Possibly. I
don't know.
But in today's context in 21st century
warfare, it's drones and missiles that
are the key the critical uh weapons that
uh that win or lose wars. So I think
Iran is way ahead on in those two
things. Right. Omni says, "How come the
US doesn't have any answer to Iran's
underground offensive capability?
Does the US have technological
limitations regarding their bunker
buster bombs?" Okay, Iran knows what
American bunker buster bombs can do.
They can penetrate maybe 60 m below the
surface of the earth into bedrock. Not
bedrock, but 60 m. Okay,
as as much as 60 m below the earth's
surface.
Let's let's first of all verify that.
How deep can American bunker buster
bombs penetrate?
How deep? How deep? 60 ft. Not 60 m. 60
ft.
Okay. Okay. Okay. 60 m or 60 ft. What is
it? 200 ft. Let's say it's 60 m of
reinforced concrete.
60 m.
60 m of reinforced concrete. So if you
are Iran and you know that the Americans
their bombs can penetrate 60 m below the
surface reinforced concrete let's say
100 m just to be safe
then all you have to do is you build
your facilities 500 m down
then what will the Americans do what can
they do so the Iranians have been aware
of America's capabilities for a very
long time and they have planned and
executed accordingly
so it looks like Iran's underground uh
tunnels and and
whatever installations,
storage sites, etc., launch sites, all
of that a vast network. Apparently, it
looks like these u Iranian assets are
very deep, maybe half a kilometer deep
under this earth's surface. So, American
bunker busters simply can't reach there.
Simply can't reach there. That's the
simple answer, right?
So that's why the Americans haven't been
able to really do much about Iran's uh
underground offensive capabilities.
Kakashi says, "Please talk about Idi
Amin and Robert Mugab."
Idi
um
Tanzania, right? Robert Mugab, Zimbabwe.
So Idi was the dictator of Tanzania.
I think Tanzania Idi Amin
sorry Uganda Uganda.
So he was the u dictator of Uganda
and um he was uh well he tried to
ethnically cleanse Uganda of uh all
non-UN of non-African people and uh that
included Indians and Arabs mostly
Indians. So the Indians who lived in
Uganda were forced to flee from Uganda.
Most of them went to the UK and the west
and some of them I suppose some of them
was would have come to India.
So there were Indians who lived in
Zanzibar and the east coast of Uganda
and Indians of Uganda. They all had to
flee from Uganda and yeah it was a
pretty brutal dictator. There are
allegations he was a cannibal. I don't
know about how how true that is or not
but that sort of thing. and that
destroyed Uganda's economy. But because
much of Uganda's economy was dependent
on Indians,
that destroyed Uganda's economy. So
that's about Idi and Roat Mugab was the
dictator of Zimbabwe who was in power
until the 2010s
and he Zimbabwe was in was earlier known
as Rudesia named after the the the the
brutal Cecil roads the guy who was
responsible for so much slavery and
misery in Africa. Cecil roads, Rudesia
and Ug and and Zimbabwe was after
Rhdesia was uh was freed from white
occupation from European occupation. um
it gave rise to the nation called
Zimbabwe
and Robert Mugawi was the leader of the
that nation for a very long time until
the 2010s maybe late 2010s and um it is
alleged that he was very
anti- European anti-white and um during
his time a lot of land was stolen from
the white people which obviously was not
theirs to begin with but whatever that
sort of thing. So that's about that's
about these two gentlemen in brief.
Vishal R says if you
okay first of all you used to practice
weak plus fasting but how you used to
gain 5 to 7 kilogram in small b of days
before starting that secondly how will
Russia retaliate yes I've done extended
fasting in the past in 2020
I did a 21-day water fast in which I
only drank water no food at all 21 days,
21 days.
And then in the same year, a few months
later, I did a 23-day water fast. 23
days without any food, only water. And I
have a different channel called Abijit
Chava Vlog on which I vlogged every
single day. Just brief updates. And you
can see me visibly shrinking
and slimming down, right? So yeah, the
first one was 21 days without food, only
water. Second was 23 days without food,
only water. And then I've done a 14-day
fast also. I've done 7-day fasts. That
sort of thing. So yes, uh I would not
recommend you all do that. Okay? It's
not for everybody. It's very very tough,
very brutal. It's not easy at all and it
may affect your health very badly. It's
not for everybody. So please don't
because I did such things. You don't
have to do it. Um how did I used to gain
5 7 kilograms in a small matter of days
before starting that you don't gain 57
kilograms in 5 days right you take time
to gain the weight if you want to do an
extended fast you have to make sure you
have extra weight in your body
okay look my height is 61 if I am 75 kg
it is that is the ideal 75 80 kg is the
ideal weight for me and if I am at the
right weight ideal weight I should it it
is dangerous us to do an extended fast
if you are at at the right weight. But
if you are let's say 5 to 10 kilos
overweight then it's fine to do a
reasonably extended fast.
So you should always have extra weight
on you before you ex you attempt any
extended fast otherwise it is dangerous
for you. It can be life-threatening for
you.
So you don't gain that weight in a small
matter of days. You spend a couple of
months, two, three months gaining that,
you don't get it in a few days. Okay,
next. How will Russia retaliate? I have
no idea. It depends on Mr. Putin
entirely. Yeah, we'll see.
Right angle says Chad GBD says the
Gotland class sub is submarine is
outdated
and why Japan will send sell India Sorya
Sorya submarine. Will overlord allow it?
BDLMD said agnify production capability
capability capacity 20 per year. Your
views? Okay. Like three four questions
in one.
>> Uh Chbd says Gautland class submarine is
outdated.
>> Yeah.
>> Um okay. I have not kept up with the
Gautland class. It's a very stealthy
submarine. It's a submarine that costs
$100 million per piece which is super
super cheap. It's cheaper than an F-35
fighter plane. It's super stealthy
and it's outdated. I mean, look at
India's submarines
when they were built. Some of them are
new like the Scorpions. The nuclear subs
are new, but some of the subs are pretty
old, right? So, I don't know what
outdated means. I think it's still very
very
capable.
Uh, next, why Japan will sell India's
Sorya sub? What's a Sorya? Shyu Shoryu
Shyu class submarine. Is Japan selling
India Shyu submarines?
It's Soryu. Soryu. I don't know. I don't
think so.
Is Japan planning to sell Soryu
submarines to India?
I don't think so. Absolutely not. Nope.
Why will they sell? There is no there is
no report of them of any plans for Japan
to sell to India.
And Japan's Soryu submarines are so
incredibly dangerous and advanced that
their decommissioned Soryu submarines
are more capable than India's present
day submarines. That's how advanced
those submarines are. That's something
that frightens China. Uh BDL MD, what's
BDL? Bhat something limited.
Bat dynamics whatever MD said agnifier
production capability capacity is 20 per
year what's my views um that is um very
very very very very low
very very low very low that's my view
the posture co says based on your
assessment do you think this war could
realistically lead to the collapse or
decline of the petro dollar system why
or why not
So
what is the petro dollar system? First
of all, let's address that. The petro
dollar system is simply the fact that
most oil producing nations,
they sell oil only in exchange for US
dollars, not for other currency.
That's historically been the case since
the 1970s at least. the Saudis, the
Kuwaitis,
um,
whoever else,
if they sell oil, it's in dollars.
That's that's the petrol system. The
Nigerians,
whoever, right? So, that's the petrol
system. And that has ensured that the US
dollar remains the most relevant and
currency in the world and the world's
reserve currency.
Now in the past few years the Saudis,
the Saudis have been selling oil to
China in exchange for Chinese yuan, not
US dollars. That is very naughty. Uh but
yeah, but mostly it's still the petro
dollar. So if this war ends in a certain
way, could that lead to the decline or
collapse of the petro dollar system? It
depends. If the US and Israel win and
Iran is defeated, then there is no
collapse of the petro dollar system. If
there is a stalemate, the war ends at
the stalemate which means that the state
of Hormos is still closed or controlled
by Iran and Iran is not defeated. There
is no regime change. In that case, what
happens is the question because the the
neighboring nations of Iran, the Gulf
nations, the UAE, Saudi Arabia, Kuwait
and so on, Bahrain, Qatar, etc.,
They were living under the illusion that
the Americans would protect them from
any Iranian attack.
And that has turned out to be a complete
illusion
because the Iranians have defeated
America's military capabilities in those
nations. The Americans have military
bases in these nations.
Most of these have been essentially
destroyed. The American fifth fleet base
in uh Bahrain has been most likely wiped
out.
So if the war ends in a stalemate, the
Americans devastate Iran but can't
defeat it and Iran's ballistic missile
capabilities and drone capabilities
remain
um this they still continue then the
Gulf nations
they will be
in the situation
where they may have to accept Iranian
primacy in the region
instead of American primacy in the
region.
If the Americans are forced to withdraw
from the region militarily, then Kuwait,
Qatar, Bahrain and so on so forth may
have to accept that Iran is the big dog
in the region, top dog in the region.
And then Iran may say you sell oil, you
have to sell in Chinese one or whatever.
In that case, that can lead to the
decline and perhaps collapse of the
petroleum system.
Or maybe that doesn't happen. So, it's
it's a 50/50 if there is a stalemate.
But if Iran wins
and America is expelled from the region,
then the petro dollar system declines,
possibly even collapses.
Siddhi Gigawoker says, "Your opinions on
Van Djk and six Ukrainians arrested.
I am not surprised at all.
This has been going on for a very long
time. So these individuals, what why why
have they been arrested? This Van Djk is
a mercenary. He's most likely an
American covert operative. He has been
involved in all kinds of regime change
operations, whether it is Libya, whether
it is Iraq, whether it is whatever else.
Okay. He he has a documented history of
being involved in various American
regime change regime change operations.
Very dangerous guy, regime change
expert. He was also there in Bangladesh
apparently when the Americans did the
regime change against Shik Hassina in
2024.
And this guy Van Djk has been crossing
over from either Manipur or Misam into
Burma, Myanmar. And he and these
Ukrainian mercenaries and other
individuals
have been training cookie terrorists
in drone warfare and other things. And
they have been supplying these cookie
terrorists with drones.
The question is how they most likely
crossed over from Mizoram which is south
of Manipur into Myanmar to train the
cookie terrorists. The question is how
look
if you want to enter these states
Manipur, Misoram etc you need something
called an innerline permit.
Even if you are an Indian citizen and
you want to visit the states, let's say
you land at the airport in Aizaw,
Misoram, you land at the airport. Before
you exit the airport, you have to fill
out a form and get an eline permit.
They'll take you photograph of your
face. They'll ask you why are you here?
What what is what is your the purpose of
a visit? Where are you going to be
staying? Where are you from? What are
what's your background? They're going to
ask you all these questions. And
depending on whether they see you as a
threat or not, they will issue the
innerline permit to you or maybe deny
it. In which case you do go back even if
you're an Indian citizen. Now these
people are foreigners. How did they get
in innerline permits for misoram? How
did who facilitated their crossing over
into Burma?
Because they are foreigners. Somebody
must have taken them to the border on
vehicles or whatever. How did they get
drones into the region? Military drones.
Since 2023, military drones have been
used by Kokita terror risks on the
civilians of Manipur.
Even the capital of Manipur, Impal, it
had to be shut down a few times because
of drones
flown by cookie terrorists in the
region.
And the entire disaster that is
currently unfolding in Manipur, it's a
geopolitical matter.
It it the root cause of the problem is
that more than half of Manipur is is
under foreign occupation.
Lacks of cookies have crossed crossed
over into Manipur and set up artificial
new villages.
They've crossed over from Burma. Some of
them allegedly have come through
Misaram. So the question is what is the
involvement of miseram also in this all
kinds of complex issues
and these cookies
they are coordinating with the church
there's church elements in this there
have been lots of various pastors
priests coming into the region and
organizing the cookie terrorists
so there's a big involvement of the
church possibly the Baptist churches
that that emanate out of the US.
And what's the role of Ukraine in this?
Ukraine is American vasal state.
Ukraine is
it still exists because the Americans
are Europe supplying it and keeping it
you know ensuring it keeps fighting the
Russians. Now when Ukraine is fighting
this war against Russia, it's a do or
die war for Ukraine, right?
And the Ukrainian government is is
drafting elderly guys into the armed
forces. It's drafting pregnant women
into the armed forces because the young
because the young guys are dead.
At that time you have this well-trained
Ukrainian armed forces personnel who
instead of fighting for the country are
coming to India and crossing into Burma
to uh to train terrorists who will then
fight Indians
and they are led by this Van Djke
person. And there are other American
church guys, special forces officers who
are now church guys who are also
involved in these matters. There are all
these videos out there on on Twitter.
You can't deny these videos, the
authenticity of these videos.
So this
my question is how how on earth is the
government of India allowing these
activities to happen?
the all these years this suddenly
erupted in 2023 the the the disaster in
Manipur it's which is still ongoing
which the media doesn't cover now but
it's still going on
um but certainly now on YouTube so not
on YouTube on Twitter etc there's this
uh looks like
looks like there's a change of mood yeah
um I think it's too early to say whether
the government of India will finally
take some action against the cookie
terrorists and those who are empowering
him.
Um I think it's too worried to say but
it's I think the arrest of Van Djk and
the six Ukrainians I think it is a
positive step and I'm hopeful that the
government of India will now perhaps
decide to take some action to end the
terrorism in Manipur against the against
the Indian citizens by foreigners. I
hope so.
Kakashi says Maduro and the Deli
Rodriguez admire Hinduism and visited
temples. I am aware of this. uh they
were disciples of uh Satya Sai Baba I
believe right yes I'm aware of this yeah
we know Vav says observation I don't
relate to pashons Punjabi sizes are blo
uh but middle and upper middle class
muhajers feel uncannily same psyche and
approach as eastern UP brahmen takur
kayasta homes insane how even household
things.
Um,
so the muhajars are essentially the
people who came who who migrated to
Pakistan from India, right? They are
those Indian Muslims who chose to
migrate to Pakistan. The majority of the
Indian Indian Muslims chose to remain in
India. But a certain number of them
chose to migrate to Pakistan. Those who
migrated from India to Pakistan are
called muhajus and a large number of
them I suppose they come from Uttar
Pradesh and so on and
look they are Pakistanis today their
religion is Islam but their blood is
ours right and they are from UP and so
whatever places UPH whatever
so they won't lose their ethnicity and
their deep culture
those things I suppose will remain. So I
am personally not aware of what the
similarities etc are but I'm I'm sure
there'll be plenty of similarities even
among the Punjabi Hindis Pton Balois
Balo people there'll be lots of
similarities with us because after all
we are all descended from the same
people right so there's going to be
similarities but I am not aware of the
specifics of what you have observed but
there is no surprise as far as I'm
concerned that these similarities exist.
Rummit Mishra says quantity overpowers
quality. Pakistan did the same thing
during operation sundur but failed
badly. We need to find cheaper way to
take down those cheap drones for any
upcoming misadventures since S400
missiles is quite expensive are quite
expensive. Okay.
Quantity will will always overpower
quantity. Quantity will will always
overpower quality. Yes. Uh true. True
that Pakistan did the same thing during
Operation Synindu but failed badly. I'll
tell you why they failed badly. They
launched hundreds of drones every night
against India and those drones maybe
each drone costs let's say $1,000 $2,000
$3,000 and India shot those drones down
with uh
with uh um bullets essentially that cost
a fraction of what the drones which each
drone costs. So India had these guns,
right? What are the guns called? Let's
let's ask the the AI.
Which automatic gun did India used
during Operation Synindor?
Um upgraded L40
40 mm anti-aircraft guns.
So let's ask it.
Um L40, right?
Uh where is it? L L70. Now L70.
How much does each round of the
Oh, sorry. How much does each round of
cost?
Let's see what it says. How much does it
cost? Ammunition,
ammunition, ammunition, ammunition.
Okay, let's say it's $345, $350 per
round. Okay, let's say it's $350 per
round and the Pakistani drone costs,
let's say, $1,000, maybe $2,000. Let's
say it's,000. So, we taking down one
drone, which is $1,000, with a $350
round.
And these guns that we that India used
were automatically targeted guns using
AI and radar. So it essentially
guaranteed that each shot will destroy
one one drone, right? It was targeted
through using radar data and AI. So
there was no human interaction, human
involvement in the targeting of the
thing. It was all done automatically and
that's why the hits were guaranteed. So
each $1,000 drone was taken down with a
three $350 uh bullet or round.
So that ensured that the economics of
war were were on our side. So the
Pakistanis launched hundreds of drones
each night all those three four nights
and India took down each each and every
one of those drones. So you understand
please this that we destroyed the
Pakistani drones using bullets or
anti-aircraft rounds which were which
were cheaper than the drones. We did not
use hundreds of S400 missiles to destroy
hundreds of drones. The S400 is for a
different purpose entirely. We have a
multi-layered air defense system to
destroy cheap drones. We have those L70
guns, anti-aircraft guns. Then to
destroy other kinds of other classes of
incoming targets, we have the Akash
system. Akash surfaceto-air missile
system essentially to destroy
helicopters, fighter aircraft and so on.
And then we have the S400 system that
also can destroy incoming cruise
missiles, perhaps ballistic missiles,
definitely aircraft. So it's a
multi-layered system that we have,
right? So we already have a very cheap
way of taking down drones. The economics
are on our side not on the not on the on
the Pakistani side. So we have done a
great job of this actually.
Push says Saddam Hussein decided to sell
oil
in euros instead of US dollars which
would which would benefit Europe. So why
is it that the EU nations sided with the
US and remote Saddam? Very simple
answer. The EU nations are American
vasals. Even if Saddam Hussein was on on
their side, the Americans could arm
twist the Europeans into doing whatever
the Americans wanted. It's as simple as
that. The EU nations are American
vasals. They were American vasals at the
time. And as vasals, you are essentially
forced to do whatever the overlord
orders you to do. Otherwise there are
very very bad circumstances
situation consequences consequence very
bad consequences okay that's why
Jimmy says post Mandela South Africa
down don't fall my views um
um yeah looks like the South African the
nation of South Africa is not as well
governed today as it was uh post
Mandela's post Mandela let's say post
Mandela
Maybe the the governance is no longer
that good. I I I hear that there are
parts of South Africa where there's a
lot of crime, South African cities where
it's dangerous to go into and so on. So
it's unfortunate and hope I hope things
get better for the nation of South
Africa. Wonderful nation.
Dur Kamat says Hindu genocide is the
gravest crime against humanity. I agree
with you like I said and none of our
historians have bothered to research
this or or speak about this or document
this. Nobody has done this. It's the
worst crime against humanity. I would
say at least
500 million Indians would have died in
that at least over a period of 700 years
which is less than a million a year.
Okay. Prattana says India did not
abstain. AI lied. Okay. Let's find out
once again.
Um what was the what was the uh
resolution?
Uh at transatlantic trade. Okay.
United Nations transatlantic slave trade
resolution.
Let's see.
Um
voting
voting results. Let's see.
D let's see I forget about AI let's see
what um
voting results
declaration of the blah blah action what
is this chair blah blah blah this is
just a long text
Ghana
oh please Microsoft take a hike
UN votes to decide describe
Does it say anything about India? It
says nothing about India.
India. Let's see.
Al Jazzer. Do we have anything from
India? New Indian Express.
D. Have they just copy pasted uh western
talking points? What did India do in
this? India.
Come on. So this is an article in the
Indian Express.
This is where did it go?
Okay. Let's see if there is any mention
of India in this.
So this is clearly copy pasted from the
west. Yeah, this is an article in the
Indian Express but it doesn't mention
India. How India voted. So, I don't
know. I can't find anything and I'm I'm
not going to waste everyone's time
looking into this, but okay.
24 Bat says, "Can you please stop using
the weak Google AI to retrieve your
info? It's annoying me." Please leave if
it's annoying you, sir. I am doing
whatever I can do as fast as possible.
But let me see once. You also saying
India voted for the slavery resolution.
That's interesting.
So, look, first of all, u if you don't
want me to use something
Do you have a better option that you can
give me instead of simply complaining?
I am not here trying to, you know, I'm
trying to do the best I can here. This
is the fastest, easiest option I have.
Now, since all of you are saying it's AI
is lying, that's very interesting and
I'm I'm going to look into it.
Um,
once again, let's look into this.
United Nations transatlantic slave
trade.
Let's see.
UN news.
Okay, let's see here. Green is in favor
of right. What do we have? What do we
have? India seems to be in favor of the
resolution. You're right all of you.
Three countries voted against. So,
Israel voted against, red, Argentina
voted against, US voted against. And the
yellow nations are those who abstained.
Switzerland, Sweden, Lithuania,
Luxembourg, New Zealand,
Norway, Finland, France and India voted
in favor of this resolution.
Okay. But the Google AI is lying to us.
That's very interesting. Very
interesting.
So once again, let's ask the Google AI.
In the recent UN vote, no, forget that
UN resolution about the transatlantic
slave trade. What was India's vote?
AI mode.
What was India's vote? India abstained.
India voted in favor of the resolution.
Why are you saying that it abstained?
Let's see what it says.
Okay, so it's trying to
see UN news.
UN news.
Let me see.
Let me try and argue with the EI.
India
voted in favor
favor of the resolution.
See image.
Let's see what it says now.
I understand the confusion. It's from a
different UN session.
So in Okay, looks like this is a
different session.
I have no idea.
Okay. So,
okay. Looks like there is some
confusion. The AI is adamant that India
was voted against the resolution.
Uh multiple people here are telling me
India voted in favor of it. It's
annoying some of my viewers.
Okay. But look, I'm going to continue
using the tools that I have at my
disposal. Uh that's until I can find
better tools. I usually just do Google
searches, but now Google is throwing up
its AI generated things. So, one just
uses it. Okay. Herman Bavija says, "If
Pakistan enables a GI, a ground invasion
into Iran while attacking India to
distract, does it risk India, Iran,
Afghanistan aligning together to wage
war? Pakistan will not attack Iran or
facilitate a ground invasion of Iran
while fighting India at the same time.
It is stupid.
Uh
attacking India to distract distract
whom? It will itself be distracted if
it's attacking India while facilitating
ground invasion on on on the other
border. It uh doesn't make a lot of
sense.
and attacking India is is uh well it
essentially guarantees defeat for
Pakistan. India is just too powerful for
Pakistan.
So it makes sense to distract using
Afghanistan and not not using India
doesn't make sense to attack India for
Pakistan.
Other says go to this location on Google
maps in satellite mode. We can see
Panchamuki Hanuman and other figures.
What causes these?
Okay, let's try that.
Let us try that. Let's see. Let's go to
Google Maps
and I will go to satellite mode later.
Let's see. Minus 55.5
22 68
and - 69.2
66 22. Let's see.
And let's go to um
let's go to satellite. Yes. So where is
this
punchoki Hanuman?
Okay. First of all, what place is this?
Let me zoom out.
Oh, it's Chile.
This is Cape Horn almost. It's almost
Cape Horn.
So now if I go here there is punchuki
hanuman.
Um
okay so where is panchamuki hanuman?
Yeah there are some some
artifacts that could perhaps look like
humanoid faces or something.
You mean this here is this punchuk one?
I am not sure what you are referring to
sir.
Is this Hanuman somewhere? This could be
anything. It does look like human faces
here. It does look like some human
faces. But I would not the first thing
that would come to my mind would not be
Hanuman when I see this. 1 2 3 four
I don't know there are four
things that look maybe five things that
look like human faces but they do not
look like hanuman to me to for to for me
maybe for you it's hanuman maybe but for
me it's not so I have no idea what this
is it's interesting that we have this
thing here that looks like human faces
but we humans have this tendency to see
faces everywhere don't we have this
tendency as human beings
um to see faces in everything wherever
there are certain patterns.
So yeah, what causes this? I think it's
what it's our human tendency tendency to
see faces in everything. That's probably
what causes us to maybe imagine that
this is this is Hanuman.
Rahul Rahul says Iran's uranium
extraction site hit by Israel. Yes, I
did discuss this uh in the beginning of
this live stream. Indeed. Yes.
Ra says, "Please search law 27 in 48
laws of power." Okay, let's do that.
Let's do that. What is it about?
Law 27 in the 48 laws of power.
What is it? Law 27.
Play on people's need to believe to
create a cult-like following.
Okay.
Yeah. Yeah. You can be a cult leader of
some kind if you do that.
Um I referred to that law due to
religious fight in the chat. There a
religious fight in the chat. Okay. I am
not monitoring the chat so I don't know
but okay.
Narish says, "Who is benefiting from the
war? Trump's ratings after
who is benefiting from the war thus far,
it's China that's benefiting from the
war. But if the Gulf, if the straight of
Horus remains closed for a long time,
even China uh gets hurt progressively
more and more over time. Um so who
benefits? I think nobody's benefiting at
this point in time. The Americans are
not winning. They are looking like fools
right now. Iran is being pounded very
badly. It's being hurt very badly.
Israel is being hurt very badly. India
is suffering because is beginning to
suffer because of a shortage. Well, if
this situation continues, there will be
a shortage of uh oil and gas. That will
be bad for India. India will be hurt.
China will be hurt. Japan will be hurt.
Who wins? Who's who benefits?
Long-term.
Who benefits? Right now, it's a disaster
for everybody. Nobody's benefiting.
Trump wants to somehow find to he wants
to somehow engineer a victory out of
something. I'm not sure what victory is
going to engineer.
So right now no one's benefiting. This
is this is a disastrous situation.
Lakshadep Bhak says Pakistan just
threatened Israel that the will be out
what?
Pakistan just threatened Israel that the
will beat out of then the if the will.
What are you saying?
they threatened Israel that they will
beat out of them if they will attack
their embassy in Iran.
Uh so Pakistan is threatening Israel
that
if if if Israel attacks Pakistan's
embassy in Iran then they will take some
action.
Okay. Is the US Israeli ass? That's a
good question.
The way the way things have gone in this
war, the Israelis essentially dragged
the Americans into this war. Maybe it's
a very good and very a question we
should take seriously.
Stoikbot says, "Are you concerned about
the increase in hatred farming against
Indians in the US? What specific
interests are fueling this division and
why now?"
I think it's concerning.
there is an increase in
at least um online
uh manifestations
or or expressions of hatred against
Indians. A lot of that is coming out of
the US, right? A lot of that is there.
Um a lot of this is because of
engagement farming on uh social media
platforms like Twitter like X where if
you say something hateful which doesn't
technically uh go against the terms of
service then you will get a lot of
engagement from Indians. So if you just
say something hateful against Hindus or
Indians
then you get a lot of engagement from
Indians who get all you know upset and
that makes you money that that that that
railon bucks right uh so that's a very
easy way of farming for engagement and a
lot of American accounts are doing that
and there is also
well you know
an increase
in hindu phobia or or or
um a dislike towards Indians in the US.
U a lot of that comes out of MAGA.
Uh you know there's been this propaganda
that Indian H1B visa holders they steal
American jobs. They steal the jobs of
Americans
and uh Indians are an easy target in the
US right Indians don't fight back.
Indians aren't as well organized as
let's say the the the Muslims or the
Jewish people which are close-knit
communities and they look out for each
other. Hindus don't do that. So Indians
are a soft target.
Right? So because of these factors
there's been this increase in what you
call hatred farming against Indians in
the US. What specific interests? It's
all these interests, right? Uh MAGA
doesn't like Indians. MAGA is very ba is
very racist. A lot of the MAGA crowd is
is racist, right? And they they hate all
other races, but the Indians are the
ones they can target openly. Others,
they can't. That's why they go after
Indians. Um, and engagement farming and
so on. So, these are the the interests
that are fueling these uh yeah these
these behaviors online.
Vish should I access? Namaskar.
Namaskar. If you want to fix and improve
our hard power, where would you start
from? In here in Dank. Um, you got to
fix your hard power, you
see,
you have to fix your military. You have
to be very dangerous.
The more dangerous you are, the greater
is your hard power.
So, how do you fix your hard power? See
imagine this hypothetical scenario
right now we are seeing the Americans
have tried to destroy Americans and
Israelis together teamed up ganged up
tried to destroy Iran and they have been
hit very hard
right so now the world can see what Iran
is capable of Iran's hard power is
really high high they are a hard hard
retaliator
right now imagine a hypothetical
scenario where India is attacked in the
same manner
Can India dist whoever is attacking
let's say they come with 50 ships to
attack India 50 ships and aircraft
etc to attack India does India have the
capability to take out 50 ships and all
those aircraft
does India have the capability to let's
say hypothetically destroy nearby
military bases of of of enemies
I'm not very sure about that India still
thinks that we will fight aerial wars
with fighter planes doing uh dog
fighting. That's a 20th century mindset
that we have. So if we want to improve
our hard power, we have to have a
stockpile of a of several million drones
and a few lakh missiles.
That's where I would start from. Easy
fix begin with that various kinds of
missiles. ballistic missiles and India
only thinks of ballistic missiles as
something that will deliver nuclear
weapons.
We have to stop thinking like that.
Ballistic missiles should be used for
everything, not just nuclear delivery.
They should be used like the Iranians
are using them for conventional for the
delivery of conventional munitions and
submunitions.
And look at the advancements the
Iranians have brought about in ballistic
missiles, maneuvering warheads,
subcluster submunitions and so on.
India doesn't have those capabilities
and it's not that hard to to to develop.
So India I would how would I start? I
would invest in tens of thousands of
cruise missiles, tens of thousands of
ballistic missiles total. In total, I I
would want to have at least a stockpile
of at least a lack missiles of various
kinds of various ranges and I would like
to have an inventory of perhaps a at
least a million drones of various kinds
and those drones have to be very capable
in different ranges and al and so on.
That's what I would start from.
If you do that, you don't even need an
air force essentially. And then there's
so many other steps you can take. You
should I would also focus on the navy. I
would want to uh distribute the
lethality lethality of the navy instead
of concentrating it in big ships like
aircraft carriers. Aircraft carriers are
obsollet officially now. Okay. I would
invest in submarines. I would want India
to have at least 50 submarines and I
would want India to have at least two or
300 missile boats to defend India's
coastline. Then let's have an invasion.
50 ships, 100 ships will wipe wipe you
out. So that's what I would do. That's
how that's where I would start. That's
where that's what I would begin with.
Okay. Anik says, "Please ask AI trans
bill 2026. You will be pleased to with
the government." Okay.
Trans bill 2026.
What is that? What does AI have to say?
Okay. AI. So I'm once again AI may be
lying to us. Okay. The transgender
person's protection of rights uh
amendment act bill was passed by the
Indian parliament March 2526.
The bill amends the 2019 act and has
sparked what does it say? Removal of
selfidentification.
It deletes section something of the 2019
act effectively removing the legal right
for a person to self-determine their
gender identity. Good. Good.
Identity recognition now requires
verification by a government appointed
medical board. A district magistrate
issues a certificate only after
examining this board's recommendation.
The definition of a transgender gender
person has been narrowed. It now
specifically includes individuals with
socioultural identities like hij kers,
aravani, jtda and those with biological
interex variations while explicitly
excluding those with self-p perceived
identities. Good. We are saying no to
wokeism.
Uh okay. Punishments against for crimes
against transgender persons. Very good.
Good. Um, right.
Okay. So, you are right. I am pleased.
This is an anti- vocism bill. So,
transgender persons do exist and this
bill takes it. It protects their rights
and gives them more legal resource if
there is any crime committed against
them. But the bill says that you know
nobody can identify selfidentify as
transgender
because the Americans have introduced
this new nonsense right in the past few
years you can identify as whatever you
want
he him she her they them and there are
what all kinds of weird identities have
people have come of this uh what fries
and what
whatn not so I'm I'm glad I'm so glad
that the government of India is doing
this We are purchasing $25 billion worth
of Russian equipment and weapons and we
are slamming the door shut on wokeism.
The Americans will be really really
displeased with us today.
Really displeased.
India very bad. Very bad sir. Very bad.
Very bad. Okay.
Uh Suman Vikran says missed my super
chat made yesterday in the comments. I
have taken every single super chat
that's come in front of me. So I'm sorry
if you have put something yesterday that
was not shown to me by YouTube but I am
trying my level best to answer every
single super chat and I've done I've
answered every single super super chat
that has come in front of me. Now who
decides to put this in front of me? It's
YouTube that gives me a list of super
chats. Okay. So I am sorry that this has
happened but it's not done by me. It's
done by YouTube if it was not shown to
me. I'm sorry about that. Very sorry
about that.
24 Bat says surely Greenland is US Vasal
already. Cuba is next. Greenland is not
a separate country.
So saying that Greenland is a US vasal
is like saying that Balojasthan is a
Soviet vasal
Balojasthan is not a separate country
right today. It's part of Pakistan.
Saying Greenland is is a US vasal is
like saying that uh that that that that
uh Cind
is a Chinese vasal. How can Sind be a
Chinese vasal? Pakistan can possibly be
a Chinese vasal but Sind can't. Right. S
is a subset of Pakistan. So Greenland is
a subset of Denmark.
Okay.
Yes. But larger picture what you're
saying I agree. The US already has de
facto control over Greenland. They
already have their military in
Greenland. They have military bases in
Greenland. So yeah, that Americans like
I agree have de facto more or less
control over Greenland and they can just
walk in and take over. There's nothing
nothing Denmark can do to oppose them,
right? So yeah, that's that's true. Cuba
could very much be next. You know, if
Donald Trump wants to salvage his broken
ego, then he could go and take Cuba
next. Cuba uh they don't have missiles,
they don't have drones, they have
nothing compared to what Iran has. So
it'll be way easier possibly for the US
to take over Cuba. It could be next.
Yes.
Rumit Mishra says getting fuel from
plastic and biomass is possible. I did
my Btech in chemical engineering final
year project on this topic and we did
get some yield of bofuel. So it is
indeed possible. So you were able to do
this as a student in your BTech chemical
engineering. So imagine there are people
who are experienced chemical engineers
maybe 10 years 20 years of experience.
Imagine the efficiency
with which they can extract
fuel from biomass. Right?
So let's say you got some yield of
bofuel
maybe their their the amount of bio fuel
they will get through their processes
through because of their experience and
expertise will be maybe 10 times more
potentially. So it certainly can be
done. You can extract fuel from plastic
and from biomass indeed. And that is a
huge opportunity for India. But for for
it to become possible, we're going to
have to set up the infrastructure all
across India.
And we're going to have to do it
efficiently without any wastage and
without any alleged corruption.
And we'll have to do it quickly in the
next couple of years. So it's going to
it can be done. It can be done. And that
could make India significantly
self-sufficient in at least
possibly diesel and also cooking gas.
It's certainly very much possible
because we have a tremendous amount of
biomass that comes out of waste, kitchen
waste and other other waste from
households, right? With a population of
1.4 4 billion.
It's a huge opportunity for India
and we have a lot of plastic waste also
in this country in India. So I think
that's a tremendous opportunity for the
government of India to uh to invest in
this to invest in this infrastructure.
It's not going to be easy. It's going to
cost a lot of money but it will make
India significantly more self-sufficient
than what we are right now.
Is it financially
viable? I suppose it should be. Yeah.
Yeah. I hope the government takes this
very seriously.
Anik says if the F-35, the American F-35
can take a hit, imagine what will happen
to the J20 F35 copy. There are there are
rumors that as soon as the J20 takes off
near the Indian border, it gets locked
in by Indian radar and that's why the
designers of the J20 the designer of the
J20 young way was found dead after
removal. JTBC.under undermining Chinese.
Uh, please do podcast with General Rajiv
Narayan.
Um,
so the Iranians were able to hit the
F-35. They were able to hit an F-35, one
F-35
and the J20, the Chinese,
the Chinese copy of the F-35.
I suppose it can also be then you know
uh
be targeted by by by by
missiles or whatever. Uh the Iranians
seem to be using a different technique
to acquire a lock onto American
aircraft. So typically you have radars.
You have radars that ping the aircraft
and then the aircraft knows that you
have been pinged. You've been locked on
locked on to but if you instead of using
radars if you use heat signatures if
you're close enough then I suppose
without using radars you can lock onto
aircraft. The F-35 I'm sure has a big
heat heat signature there's a very small
radar cross-section but the heat
signature is much bigger. So if you are
close enough to the aircraft, you can't
do it from far away I suppose but if you
are reasonably close enough maybe a few
kilometers or something you may be able
to acquire the heat signature and you
can use that to have a missile lock onto
the target instead of using radar and
then the aircraft which is being locked
on will not even know about this. So uh
that's I think what the Iranians seem to
have done and uh if the F-35 can be hit
so can the J20. Now there's rumors of u
I don't know about the story of young
wei being found dead and all
I don't I don't I don't know about that.
I can't comment about the young way's
death or not. I'm not aware of this. Uh
please do podcast with Rajiv with
General Rajiv Narayan. I did one. It's
been released just a couple of hours
ago.
Uh it is on the Avara Musafer podcast.
Yeah. So, it's out just a couple of
hours ago, I think.
V for Valor says, "Russia Israel
relations and common anti-Nazism views.
Does US deep state not allow Israel to
come close to Putin who is a known
anti-Nazi?
Also, how are Ukraine Israel relations?
Does the US deep state not allow Israel
to do something or the other? The US
deep state doesn't
doesn't get to tell Israel what to do.
I think it's possible that Israel may be
the US deep state. It's possible. I'm
just speculating, but who knows? So, the
US deep state doesn't give orders to
Israel. That I can assure you of. Israel
decides what it does.
Now, what is the deal with the Israel
Ukraine relations? Well, in case you are
not aware, the president of Ukraine,
Shiri Zalinski, is Jewish,
which guarantees that Israel and Ukraine
have excellent relations.
And Mr. Putin is fighting against
Ukraine, against Mr. Zalinsky, which
means that Russia Israel relations will
not be very good right now. Anti-Nazism,
that's that's obsolete stuff. Who cares?
I mean there was there were recent
resolutions in the UN against Nazi
ideology. I think u Israel voted on the
wrong side in that
so Nazi ideology it's it's obsolete.
Nobody cares about that anymore. Every
nation has its own interests and they
follow it, you know, irrespective of of
ideology.
Let's ask the Google AI about that,
right?
In the last 3 years, was there any
resolution in the United Nations um
condemning Nazi ideology?
Yes. Okay. Adopted resolutions annually.
That's very interesting. Nazi ideology.
Let's see. Let's see. Okay. Pastor
How did Israel and the United States
vote in these resolutions?
Let's find out.
So the resolutions were about combating
glorification of Nazism and the US said
no we don't want to combat glorification
of Nazism and Israel said no we don't
want to combat glorification of Nazism
Israel said no we don't want to combat
glorification of Nazism we are against
combating glorification of Nazism
All right.
Okay.
So, Nazism, anti-Nazism, all that
nonsense, nobody cares even in Israel
today, right? Just because Putin is
anti-Nazi doesn't mean that he is Israel
is going to like him. Okay. All right.
24 Bat says since 2014, Western social
media media have turned anti-India.
Uh 2014, yeah, Mr. Modi came to power
and yes Hindu nationalist bad guy etc.
and uh he did a lot of good for India.
He you know
turned India's economy around built a
lot of infrastructure made India more
visible more powerful geopolitically
and obviously a lot of media a lot of
western nations will will have been very
unhappy about that so it's true and it's
been even more so since 2022 when the
Russians launched the special military
operation in Ukraine and India refused
to condemn it India refused to join and
participate in western sanctions against
Russia. And on the other hand, India
started buying large quantities of
Russian oil. So after 2022, it's been
even more anti-India. Whether it is the
western media, whether it's social
media, whether it is think times,
whether it is BBC, CNN, Guardian,
whatever, everybody just overly totally
anti-India. And their reportage of India
during COVID was atrocious. Atrocious So
I agree with you. Yes.
Dwap Priya Mukharji says big fan from
Kolkata. Thank you so much Dwapri G.
Thank you. Uh tell me tell me what do
you think if Iran wins this war what
what would happen then? And judging by
the current situation will Israel
destroy the Iranian regime.
Okay
let's ask the second answer the second
question first. Will going by the way
things are right now will Israel destroy
the Iranian regime? I think it is very
unlikely that Israel will succeed in
destroying the Iranian regime. Why do I
say this? Because the Iranian regime is
fault tolerant.
What do I mean by that? It's like a
distributed fault tolerant network with
lots of nodes.
You destroy a few nodes,
it doesn't destroy the system.
The system is not made of glass that you
destroy. You poke it once and the whole
thing shatters. It's not like that. It's
distributed and fault tolerant. You can
destroy multiple nodes and the system
still functions.
You you kill the ayatah, it doesn't
affect the system. You kill the supreme
leader, the system generates a new
supreme leader without any loss of
continuity or functionality.
You kill 50
uh top commanders, they've come up with
50 more.
You you nuke one city, Iran still keeps
fighting.
They have made sure that the system is
fault tolerant. The IRGC, see
this, the power in Iran doesn't lie in
the hands of the ayatah. It it lies in
the hands of the IRGC. And the IRGC is
distributed.
It's not one person. No one person is
important IRGC. The IRGC is more
important than any individual. It's more
important than even the Ayatah. The
Ayatah simply gives legitimacy and
personification to the IRGC. But the
Ayatah is not that important. He is an
important symbol, religious symbol for
the Iranians. But his death makes no
difference to the IRGC Iranian Iranian
revolutionary guard core.
Right? So because of these reasons and
because the Iranians have perhaps more
than a lack drones and tens of thousands
of ballistic missiles, they're going to
keep fighting. If they run out of drones
and missiles, they're going to fight
handtoand if required.
And launching a ground invasion of Iran
is as Saddam Hussein discovered
suicidal.
And without launching a ground invasion,
you can't do a regime change. You can't
ever
successfully conduct a regime change
from altitude. You have to have boots on
the ground. So that's why it is in my
opinion at this point in time the way
things are very unlikely that that
Israel will be able to destroy the
Iranian regime. They may kill more
leaders, more commanders, but that won't
make any difference. The Iranians will
keep fighting. This will give rise to
the to the to the to the it will give
rise to the ascent of more and more
hardline and younger leaders and
commanders, which is bad actually for
Israel.
Um so yeah it doesn't look like Israel
will be successful at the way things are
in destroying the Iranian regime. Now
what happens if Iran wins this war wins
this war? If Iran wins what does it what
is the definition of victory from Iran's
perspective? The definition of victory
from Iran's perspective is to survive
the war.
To survive the war. If the Americans
can't destroy the leadership and and the
IRGC, then they can't occupy Iranian
territory, that's a victory for Iran.
The fact that Iran remains sovereign at
the end of the war is a victory for
them. But beyond that, what could be the
definition of an Iranian victory? A
bigger victory for Iran would be the
complete destruction of all the American
military bases in the region, which most
likely has already happened.
If the if the war ends with the
Americans unable to return to those
military bases or reconstruct them,
that's a huge victory for Iran. If the
Iranians
successfully
persist in keeping the straight of
Hormos closed or selectively closed,
it's a huge victory for Iran. yet. Um,
so
so if that happens, it could be the end
of the petro dollar system
and the whole balance of power in the
region would change completely
and it would be totally a different
world order. It doesn't mean that the
Americans will no longer be the most
powerful nation. They'll still be the
most powerful nation, but their uh their
myths and aura of invincibility will be
shattered very badly if Iran wins this
war.
And that will have effects everywhere.
It will give other nations way more
leverage against the Americans than
right now
as is right now visible with India.
India is openly now pivoting towards
Russia
in just a month's time. India has more
leverage now. India has definitely more
leverage now and that will even that
will become even more if the Americans
actually um actually like visibly lose
this war. Okay.
Ritikuni says saw you with General Rajie
added to my queue fast. Thank you so
much. Thank you so very much. Thank you.
Herman Baja says does India also have
mosaic strategy like Iran? If political
and military top leadership goes
different state commands of MI
military should separately without order
IB ro
MI
should together run lead India
that's a great question actually
it's a great question
how do I answer
In warfare,
there is a slightly outdated concept.
It comes from the Prussian military
commander and theorist Carl Fon
Clausovitz.
And this concept is called the center of
gravity.
Center of gravity. It's it's an actual
military concept. It's not something you
should make fun of. Of course, when the
Pakistanis speak about it, you can make
fun of them, but it's an actual military
concept. What is a nation or a kingdom's
center of gravity? It is that
particular combination of assets upon
which everything depends.
And if you take that down, the whole
structure collapses like a pack of
cards. That's the center of gravity.
So in some nations the center of gravity
is one person.
Saddam Hussein
you take him out everything collapses.
The whole nation collapses.
I mean in the year 1066
when William of Normandy invaded England
he fought a battle at uh Hastings
Hastings against Harold King Harold.
Harold Goodwinson and the battle was
going it was neck to neck until King
Harold died. He got a stray arrow in his
eye. The moment he died his whole army
collapsed and they just ran from the
field. The center of gravity was the
person of Harold himself. One person was
the center of gravity of the whole
nation. He died the whole structure
collapsed.
In the middle ages in India, him Chundra
Vikramaditya,
right? He was the king in Delhi, the
last Hindu king, the last Hindu emperor
of Delhi. He was fighting an army
against against an army of Akbar,
Jalaludin Akbar. And Himu got an arrow
in his eye. He died and the whole
structure collapsed. So once again, the
center of gravity was the person of the
emperor.
So that's not a mosaic strategy. That's
all the power all the whole center of
gravity that's that's embodied in one
person in IRGC the mosaic strategy the
IRGC which is a distributed force
tolerant network is the center of
gravity
to defeat Iran you have to destroy the
entire IRGC which is next to impossible
so that's why Iran is so resilient even
if it is nuked even if they have to find
fight hand to hand with knives is
they'll still fight. They'll not give
up. They also have this people's war
approach that Maung had because of the
ideology, the Shia ideology and so on.
Now what about India?
What is India's center of gravity? I
wonder. India doesn't have a mosaic
strategy at all.
India doesn't have it. India is way more
vulnerable from a center of gravity
perspective
compared to Iran.
Yeah.
So if India's hypothetically okay
political
military top leadership goes I'm not
sure how well the
armed forces will are in a position to
keep fighting individually separately.
Uh I'm not sure about that. Maybe these
things are classified and we are not
supposed to know about them. Maybe we
have that but if we have that it's not
disclosed to the public. So hopefully we
have all these you know fallback options
etc. Hopefully we will have that but I
am not aware of it. Maybe we we are not
supposed to know about this.
Okay
24 says what's your favorite James Bond
film? Ah
um as a kid one of the first Bond movies
I watched was uh The Spy Who Loved Me.
Um Roger Moore was there. Yeah Roger
Moore. Uh, but I think my favorite Bond
was James was was was Sean Conry. Dr. No
was great.
Thunderball was great.
You Only Live Twice was outstanding.
Moonreaker was funny.
Um, I don't know. I'm not sure if if I
have a single favorite Bond film. I've I
was I've been a big fan of PSA also a
couple of his movies. I think um Daniel
Craig's Casino Royale was great
actually.
Some of the later movies have been kind
of let downs.
I'm not sure which is my favorite Bond
movie.
Uh must must be one of the Shan Conry
movies pro perhaps
perhaps
you live only twice perhaps.
Um, yeah, I I like the whole series, you
know, many movies. There's no one
specific movie that stands out as my
favorite. But yes, my favorite James
Bond was Shan Conor.
Mama Bucket VFX says, "Us burning oil
like we got zero PT energy or do they
zero PT energy?"
Zero point zero point energy. Uh, I'm
not aware of Look, Zero point energy is
a quantum mechanical concept. Okay. Even
when you bring a system down, you you
cool it down to 0 Kelvin, there's still
going to be some residual energy in the
system. There's going to be some
vibration. Okay, that's called the 0
point energy.
Now,
US burning oil like we so so can we
actually extract energy out of the
concept of zero point energy? I'm I
don't know about that. I am I'm not
aware of any such thing.
um US burning oil like we got that I I'm
not aware of that but yeah the Americans
are burning oil like there's no tomorrow
for sure you know war all those climate
change things and all they go out of the
window they don't matter anymore later
once the war ends they will once again
come back to lecture us about climate
change and about energy and all that but
when they need energy they'll they'll
burn it like anything
okay
uh Dh Kamat says a certain Bobby Eens
making controversial assertions such as
Christianity being superior and Jesus
being the greatest which are deeply
offensive to Hindus.
Okay. Um All right.
U is that on my live chat? Is it?
I am not monitoring the live chat. I'm
looking at the the super chats. So I
want to be able to look into that
because there'll be lots and lots of
live chats. But okay, thank you for
letting me know. I'll look into this
later.
Mittal says, "India is again turning to
Russia for its defense and oil needs.
Isn't it helping Russia and India both
from becoming vasals? Russia of China,
India of US." Exactly.
Exactly. If India and Russia cooperate,
work together, it helps both nations, it
helps Russia against China and India
against the US. Absolutely 100% correct.
Yes. And that's why it's it's a win-win
thing for India and Russia both. It's
mutually beneficial for India and
Russia. That's why I am I have always
been a big proponent of more robust
relations between India and Russia
because Russia isn't a nation that that
that wishes India ill.
Right? Russia doesn't seek to vilize or
colonize or destroy India or destroy
destroy India civilization. Russia
doesn't have any such
such agenda but certain other nations do
have such such agendas. So India and
Russia working together makes a lot of
sense for both nations.
Ratamsuri says India versus Iran who
will win when India need to learn from
Iran. What India needs to learn from
Iran? Who will win India and Iran? India
and Iran will not fight.
Okay, we are not enemies.
There is no reason for India and Iran to
ever fight each other.
The last time there was any kind of
dispute between India and Iran was about
two and a half thousand years ago
when Dario extended his border all the
way to the Indis river.
So that was the only time that there was
some kind of friction. You will some of
you will say oh no what about Nadra?
Nadra came and destroyed Delhi and
killed one lakh people in one day. Nadr
Sha was not Persian.
Nadr Sha was a Turk who ruled Iran just
like orang was a Turk who ruled India.
Understand that? So India and Iran
there's no need for us to fight. Uh what
does India need to learn from Iran? Like
I said many times today
learn the importance of drones, high
quality drones and cheap drones and also
large quantities of ballistic and other
kinds of missiles. That's the simple
lesson India has to learn from Iran.
Okay. Invest invest in very large
quantities of drones and large
quantities of various kinds of very
scary, very dangerous, very nasty
missiles. Right.
Herman Baja says, "White guy claims
India is a joke for us. No need to fight
India. Reshape it from within via NOS's,
education, media narratives, rituals and
religion dilutes with secularism. One
side guilt install atheism equality."
Yeah.
You see you can destroy
a nation a civilization without fighting
it. Reshape it from inside.
When a nation is poor, when a nation
when the when the people have a sense of
inferiority,
it's very easy to infiltrate the nation.
When when the whole system is allegedly
super corrupt, it's very easy to
infiltrate the nation
and just destroy from eat it from within
like termites all over the place with
NOS's with with the the rotten education
system that that's full of propaganda
and distortions of India's history and
culture. The media, the entertainment
industry, the narratives
attack Indian culture, attack Indian
religion. Say India's rituals are bad,
India's religion is misogynistic,
patriarchal, whatever, whatever.
Backward. India's culture is backward.
Just keep on bombarding India's people
with this propaganda. Do it through the
education system. Do it through your
politicians. Some of them do it through
the media. Do it through the
entertainment industry.
do it decade after decade, generation
after generation and eventually the
whole civilization crumbles.
Yeah. And our system itself is our own
enemy. The entire edifice of the system
it's working against us. Our own system.
Yeah.
So yeah,
the white guy is right in this case. No
need to fight India.
godliness. If your cost of victory is
becoming another Afghanistan or Gaza
while your enemy enjoys his dinner in
New York, heritage in London and
spirituality in Jerusalem, is there a
victory standing on on ruins?
Um, it depends what what is an
acceptable cost of victory. First of
all, what is the definition of victory?
Right? There are two things here
involved. Two things are involved here.
One is what's my definition of victory?
Second is what's my cost? What's the
acceptable cost of victory?
The bare minimum victory that is
required
is preservation of sovereignty. We I
think you are discussing Iran here,
right? So let's say we discussing Iran
and from Iran's perspective the bare
minimum definition of victory is
preservation and continuation of
sovereignty that Iran no matter what
happens should remain sovereign.
Then there's the question of the price
of victory. What price are you prepared
to pay for your sovereignty?
That's the question. So
if you are being bombarded, your schools
are being destroyed, your universities
are being destroyed, your oil refineries
are being destroyed, your nuclear power
plants are being destroyed, your steel
industries are being destroyed.
Is that an acceptable cost of victory as
long as you remain sovereign? Well,
that's what that's the choice for you to
make.
What is the cost of dignity?
That's that's a choice everybody each
person has to make. Our ancestors in
India,
they gave up their millions of them gave
up their lives fighting the Turks and
the British,
right? And during the British occupation
of India, India became a Gaza. By the
way, India's uh
life expectancy in 1947 was 32.
I promise you the life expectancy in
Gaza is higher than for 32. I promise
you the life expectancy in Afghanistan
today is higher than 32. India's life
expectancy was 32.
Right? So we were worse than Gaza
but we became a sovereign nation. That's
why we are able to be where we are
today. And even now we are a poor nation
but better. So as long as you are
sovereign, even if you are ruined and
reduced to rubble, as long as you remain
sovereign somehow, you can rebuild
and maybe your children and their
grandchildren
will have a way better life.
So it's up to you. If if if for for some
people that's too high of a cost of
victory and let's just put down the arms
and surrender, well, that's your choice.
I don't think it's the right choice.
I think death is preferable to loss of
sovereignty.
Right? If you if you are a person with
self-respect,
then you would give rather die than give
up your sovereignty.
So I think Iran will prefer to become a
Afghanistan or Gaza or even worse than
that as long as it remains sovereign.
You may think otherwise that is you you
have the right to your opinion. Your
enemy is enjoying dinner in New York,
Heritage, London, Surity, Jerusalem.
Fine, that's about the enemy. And I
assure you that by the time the war
ends, um, you know,
even Israel is being hit very hard by
the way. Okay.
Okay. Praradana says, "Are defense deals
hard to keep secret to avoid sanctions?
Why the government has to publicly
announce the five more F400 deal, etc.?
Maybe I'm naive. What's your opinion?
Defense deals can be kept secret.
They can be kept secret. Yes, you can do
these deals behind closed doors and not
announce them.
And um
you can certainly make it harder for uh
enemy nations to find out about your
defense dealings with your friends,
let's say.
So
why has the government of India
announced
um the deal with the Russians? The total
quantum of the deal is about $25 billion
which is gigantic.
Huge big big sum of money.
you know, a bunch of S5 S400s, a bunch
of illusion transport aircraft, other
sorts of transport aircrafts, um,
nuclear cooperation, um, rocket systems,
anti-aircraft systems, drones, whatnot,
whole bunch of bunch of things and the
government has government of India has
announced this publicly,
right? So why are we doing this? For
some reason, India is sending a message
to the Americans.
Yeah. See before 28th of February when
the Americans and Israelis launched the
war on Iran. One day before that the
prime minister of India was in Israel
and 2 three days after the war started
India made a very clear turn towards the
US and Israel.
India refused in the first 3 4 days to
give to to even comment about the
assassination of uh the supreme leader
of Iran and India condemned the
violation of sovereignty of the Gulf
nations etc. So India was clearly taking
a stand against Iran the first 3 four
days of the war. Then India slowly
pivoted back to a neutral position. The
government of India officially gave
condolences for the death assassination
of the Ayatollah. India gave an Italian
warship refuge in an Indian port after
another ship was destroyed by the
Americans near Sri Lanka.
And the longer the war goes on, the more
India is pivoting away from the US and
Israel.
The past week or so, India arrested an
American terrorist and five or six
Ukrainian terrorists, right? Who were
giving terrorism training to cookie
terrorists. So India is as the longer
the war is going on the more India is
pivoting away from the US and now this
is a very clear message that India has
sent to the US by announcing this deal
in public.
So India is visibly pivoting away from
the US pivoting towards Russia
not towards bricks like some people
claim but towards Russia.
Yeah. So I think it's it's messaging
that's going on towards the US. India
seems to somehow have acquired more
leverage against the US than we had in
the past couple of years.
That is what I uh sense is happening.
Susant Gurj said says watching Durand
now watching Durand now I understand
what you wanted to say by that after
demonetization certain someone committed
suicide in Pakistan.
Look
now people are realizing right I spoke
about these things like three three or
so years ago I was old videos about
demonetization in which I said that
demonetization hurt Pakistan's economy
way more than it hurt India's economy
this was the beginning of the decline of
the Pakistan rupee and all those things
which went wrong in Pakistan with its
economy etc they it all happened after
demonetization
I think now people are beginning to
understand after watching this movie
Durand
what demonetization was all about. But I
spoke about this like 3 four years ago
way before Durand was imagined by the
creator. So I'm glad people are
beginning to understand this now. I
suppose it takes time to understand
certain things which is fine. Which is
fine but I'm glad that more people are
understanding. Good.
Pratepar says about pulsars and neutron
stars.
Pulsars and neutron stars. Okay. Let's
start with neutron stars. Neutron stars
are gigantic atomic nuclei.
A neutron star is made of essentially
almost only neutrons.
It's got a very thin outer crust of
exotic atomic you know nuclear
exotic matter essentially and it's got a
very very tiny thin atmosphere
of various kinds of ions I suppose and
in a neutron star you know
a neutron star is is is what it's it's a
couple of kilometers in in diameter But
it's the mass of more than the sun.
Okay?
And
mountains on a neutron star may be a
millimeter or so in height.
A mountain or a neutron star may be a
millimeter high.
But they have more mass than Mount
Everest and so on. So neutron stars um
they are produced um
um how are they produced?
How are neutron stars produced?
Okay, when a star collapses,
so our star will at the end of its life
become a white dwarf. Okay,
but if a white dwarf is
is more than 1.44 solar masses, which is
the Chundra Shakhar limit, then it
collapses into a neutron star.
And there is something called the Tolman
F tool folk openheimer limit which is
the maximum mass a neutron star can
have. And if the neutron star exceeds
that even if you put a spoonful of
matter into it then it collapses into
nothingness which is a black hole. A
black hole. So neutron star is very
compressed super compressed matter
in which even protons and and and
electrons combine to form neutrons. So
that's what a neutron star is and uh
it's the end state of many stars.
Pulsars are neutron stars that
that spin incredibly rapidly and give
off these radio pulses that are like you
can time them like a metronome. maybe 50
pulses in a second. That's that sort of
thing. And you, you know, if you have a
a shortwave radio or whatever, you can
actually detect pulsars.
They sound like that sort of thing, you
know, very rapid beeps. Initially, when
astronomers detected that through radio
telescope, etc., they thought it was
alien civilizations trying to contact us
because the pulses were so incredibly
fast and so incredibly precisely timed.
But that's simply the radio waves given
off by a very rapidly spinning neutron
star which is called a pulsar. Right.
Okay.
Urgital says some users are repeatedly
using foul language in the live chat.
Please take actions. Well, I'm not
monitoring the live chat today. Sir, I'm
okay. Let's see who is that.
Um,
okay. I don't know what's going on, but
I will look into this later on. Right
now, I am not monitoring the live chat,
so anyway, thank you for letting me
know. Thank you. I will look into this
later on. Ankita Kachab, good evening,
ma'am.
The US controls the world economy
through petro dollar and its banking
system and funds Israel on a regular
basis. Isn't Israel in a way an offshoot
of the US and helps carry out they help
carry out each other's projects? US deep
state Jewish lobby is Israel in this
sense. How is Israel benevalent to us?
How is Israel benevolent to India?
Israel's interactions with India are on
the basis of mutual interests.
So
what you are saying is correct. Um the
US controls its economy through the
petro dollar system banking system and
the and the petro dollar system. The
petro dollar and the banking system and
the US is an unconditional ally and
supporter of Israel. No question about
it.
Um, is Israel an offshoot of the US?
Well, Israel, you could say, is a
protectorate of the US, but uh, Israel
is very influential in US. Israeli
Jewish politicians and financiers and,
um, industrialists etc are very, very,
very influential and powerful in the US.
So you could say that Israel to some to
some extent may possibly control a
certain amount of certain aspect of US
foreign policy.
Right? So Israel is a protectorate of
the US.
It could be perhaps an offshoot of the
US but not quite an offshoot of the US.
It's a permanent
uh
asset, not an asset, permanent ally and
protectorate of the US and the US is
essentially duty bound to take Israel's
side no matter what happens whenever
required.
Um they do help each other carry out
each other's projects. Yeah.
And that's why I've raised the question
about Pakistan that Pakistan is an
American vasal you and Israel is
America's primary
unconditional ally or America is
Israel's unconditional ally. So what's
the connection between Israel and
Pakistan? They should be on the same
side
and uh that's the question I've raised
in the past.
And uh when it comes to this Gaza thing,
you know, um the board of peace,
Pakistan is on the board of peace. When
it comes to Gaza's reconstruction and
development, Pakistani soldiers are are
going to be involved in maintaining the
peace there on behalf of Israel
essentially. So you can see there are
there are some connections between
Pakistan and Israel.
Um a few months ago when aimir the
Pakistani dictator went to the US to
Washington DC uh the Pakistan embassy I
think in the in in that city it it uh
organized a dinner
banquet for him and there was an Israeli
military presence there in this event
organized by the Pakistani embassy in
honor of Aim Munir. So clearly there are
connections you know behind the scenes
between Pakistan and Israel. Now when it
comes to how is Israel benevalent to us?
Well overall India and Israel we have a
mutually beneficial relationship right.
Um
u for example there is
technological cooperation between India
and Israel. U India and Israel together
have jointly developed the Barak missile
system which is an anti-
which is an anti-missile system. So
let's say you are on a ship and there's
a missile coming to hit the ship, you
can destroy that with the Barak system.
The Barak system probably can destroy a
Brahmos missile. That's how powerful and
accurate it is. Um and it can also take
take out targets, you know, aerial
targets from land also. So it's a great
missile system, missile defense system
that is India and Israel have developed
jointly and India purchases all kinds of
all kinds of Israeli weapons um
manufactures some Israeli weapons in
India under license like the like the
Harop drone and so on and so forth. So
most of the cooperation between uh India
and Israel is very mutually beneficial
and so it's it's a rel relationship of
mutual benefit. It's not one nation or
the other being benevolent towards the
other. It's about both nations engaging
with each other in a mutually beneficial
way. Of course there are question marks
about Pakistan. There's also the
question mark about the Israeli
involvement,
possible potential Israeli involvement
in India's far east, northeast and so
on. There are those question marks, but
overall it's it's a good relationship
overall from a big macro perspective.
Pratip Kumar Roy says about the Hercules
Corona Borealis
Hercules Corona Borealis Great Wall. Is
it real? What's the axis of evil in
space? I have no idea about an axis of
evil in space. Um, Hercules Corona
Borealis wall. Great wall. I don't know
about this. Hercules Corona Borealis
Great Wall.
Why is it making a list?
What is this?
Largest known structure in the universe.
Massive gigantic galactic filament
measuring 10 billion light years across.
Discovered in 2013 via Gamarray bursts.
This structure defies current
cosmological models which suggest that
no structure should exceed 1.2 billion
lighty years. Okay, it's a it's a
galactic filament. What is a galactic
filament? A galactic filament is a
massive large scale structure. See the
universe at small scales looks pretty uh
inhomogeneous, right? There are there
are inhomogenities in the universe at
the small scales. But if we zoom out of
the solar system of the Milky Way of the
local cluster and zoom out further
further further further then you will
see that the universe at the largest
scales seems pretty homogeneous and
isotropic in all directions and you will
see that there are these filaments that
there are these massive galactic uh
clusters that are held together by
filaments of dark matter and so on.
So if you look at the structure large
scale structure of the universe at the
largest scales and if you look at the
galactic filaments and dark matter
filaments that hold everything together
it looks like a cross-section of neurons
from inside the brain.
Okay. So you have these galactic
galactic filaments and dark matter
filaments and this hercule corona
boralis great wall seems to be one of
these filaments. I was not aware of it
because it's not relevant to the work I
do. But it it is one of those filaments
and apparently it's too large to exist
which means that you have to rethink the
way we understand the universe. So
according to what
uh current cosmological models no
structure should exceed 1.2 billion
light years but this thing is 10 billion
light years. It's about 10 times too
large. So yeah, mystery clearly from the
astrophysics perspective. What's the
axis of evil in space? I am not aware of
any axis of evil in space. Shall we
Google that? Okay, let's Google this.
Axis of evil in space.
What's that?
Okay.
Yeah, I'm not aware of this. I'm not
aware of this.
I'm more into
theoretical physics, not into
observational astrophysic stuff, dark
matter, black holes, that sort of thing.
Pen and paper stuff, not looking at this
thing. So, okay. Omni says Iran's
underground
installations are really the master
stroke. I agree with you. Iran
has a lot of aces up its sleeve.
Definitely a master stroke. Yeah. Pratip
Kumar says, "Did you see durand? Your
views about the Israel scene? What what
was that?" Aim previous ISIS chief. I
haven't seen it yet. I haven't seen it.
Hopefully
by next weekend I will have seen it.
I will try and watch it at the earliest
in the next 3 4 days. Hopefully.
Hopefully. Uh definitely by next weekend
I will have seen it. But I haven't seen
it yet. So I won't be able to answer
these questions so far.
Mittal says please advise the pranayam
for overall health. Pranayam is a very
straightforward exercise right alternate
nostal breathing. There are different
forms of pranayam.
It's about breath control. It's about
Yeah. So I am not an expert as such in
pranayam. One thing I know about is
walking pranayam which I suppose no one
knows about. I'm sure there are people
who know about it but it's not well
known. You can do pranam while walking.
And that
can have great effects on your mind, on
your lungs, on your on your oxygenation
of your blood and your overall health.
And you can also walk a few kilometers
while doing that. Uh so you can do
pranayam while walking. It's just about
counting breathing in and out. I mean a
number of steps for an inb breath for
breathing in then a certain number of
steps steps you just hold the breath.
Then a certain number of steps you
exhale completely and then a certain
number of steps you
you keep your lungs empty and then you
repeat the cycle that's walking pranayam
essentially right so that's a great that
that has I I am most impressed by that
particular technique of pranayam
magnani says can you please can you talk
about the kalpa vigraha and how it
changes the current timelines of history
as we understand it especially for our
civilization. I am sorry to have to
disappoint you.
But I am not sure the kalpa vigra
whatever it is is a genuine thing. So it
is claimed that this object is 25,000 or
something years old. It's made of metal
and they say it's been carbon dated to
25,000 years or something 24 25,000
years. You can't carbon date a metallic
object.
The basic principle of carbon dating
is that there are certain isotopes of
carbon. There's a naughty isotope of
carbon called carbon 14. I think the
standard carbon is carbon 12. Okay,
which has 12 protons.
But there's a naughty of 12 nucleons.
But there's a naughty of carbon which is
carbon 14 which is unstable. It's
radioactive and we know at what rate it
it decays. So if you have any organic
matter
then like wood let's say you have
ancient wood that you've discovered. So
you can determine
how old it is based on how much carbon
14 it still has because the moment an
organism dies it's it starts losing
carbon 14 the carbon 14 starts decaying
decaying. We know what the half-life is
and so on. So that's how based on the
amount of carbon 14 that still exists in
a particular sample of organic matter
you can determine to a reasonable amount
of accuracy how ancient how old it is
like a piece of wood or a mummified body
or a piece of bone
right so if you find a skeleton human
skeleton and you carbon date it you can
determine how old it approximately is
500 years 2,000 years 7,000 years by
carbon dating you Find out if you find a
piece of wood you can carbonate it.
That's how we know that Dwara the
ancient city of the city of Dara which
is underwater. We discovered a piece of
wood from there and that was dated to
about 8,500 years or so before today. So
that's how we know how old the city most
likely is. Dara now if you have so so
for this to work you need organic
material which contains carbon. We are a
carbon based life form. All living
beings on our planet are carbon based
life forms. Right? So that's how we can
do carbon dating. Now if you have a
piece of metal,
how will you carbon date it when there
is only metal in it? There's no carbon.
So how can people claim that the kalpa
vigraha was dated to was carbon dated to
24 25,000 years before today? How? It
doesn't contain carbon. It is metallic.
Do you understand?
So, I don't know what this object is. I
don't take it seriously at all because
you can't carbon date something.
A piece of metal. How will you tell how
old it is?
How can somebody claim it's so and so
years old? It's a piece of metal.
There's no way of knowing how old it is.
That's my issue. So, let's see what
Google has to say about the Kalpa
Vigraha.
Kalpa Vigraha.
What is this thing? A legendary small
idol of Lord Shiva claimed to be 28,000
years old. How have you made this claim?
I don't I don't know.
Okay. Radiocarbon testing
LinkedIn posts
refers to the timber of the chest or box
holding it, not the metallic idol
itself.
which is a key scientific distinction
often missed.
Okay. So it lacks verification
historical journals.
Yeah. So listen listen I don't know
whether any
I don't know what
credence we can give to LinkedIn posts
and so on.
I will need to see an actual
you know evidence of scient proper
scientific testing of this thing. So uh
this about this matter I am extremely
skeptical.
I I'm sure it will hurt the sentiments
of some people who are seeking some
greatness out of it. But I am very
skeptical about this. I have an open
mind if this can be proven to be 28,000
years old. If somebody can actually show
me the data and and the the the readings
of the radiocarbon test of the wooden
box or whatever which contained this
thing. If we can actually find out where
this originates from not based on
LinkedIn post but actual you know
credible sources
then I can take it more seriously. Okay.
Ser Limbusu says should I chase money or
power? We have limited time on earth.
Getting everything all at once is not
possible. What's your take on it? You
should chase whatever makes sense to
you. Yeah. If you are somebody who well
who is pleased with power, who is happy
to have power, it depends on you and
your inner nature. Some people they
crave power, some people crave money,
some people crave peace in life.
Everybody craves something different.
Everybody desires
something unique to the to their own
identity and to their own personality
and their own to who they really are.
Right? So it depends. It depends
and it's not like if you chase one thing
you will get it right.
Everybody wants to chase something but
how many people actually get it? How are
very few people actually get power? You
can get power at low levels and all but
real power is something different. So I
think you have to make your decision for
yourself. You have to first understand
yourself properly. Who am I? What do I
genuinely desire and seek in life? Why
was I put on this planet? For what
purpose was I put here? Understand that
through introspection.
You have to spend time with yourself to
understand who you are. Based on that
understanding, you have to determine
what is best for you. Right? Money or
power.
Power is a very rare commodity. Money is
more abundant. Power is rare. Real power
is rare. Money, it's easier to acquire.
Power is much harder to acquire. So
remember that also. But that's entirely
up to you. I can't tell you what to do.
24 Bat says Sergio Gore is our viceroy
and our baboos are
well Sergio would certain Sergio Gore
would certainly like to be our viceroy.
But hopefully we don't allow him to
assume that position, right? The way
things are going right now doesn't look
like it's working out that well for him.
Yeah. So hopefully we don't give him the
prestige of being our vice roy.
So he would like that. But hopefully we
don't make this happen.
We are we matches. What if
hypothetically India versus Iran? Who
wins? Please tell. India and Iran we
don't fight. There's no need for India
and Iran to fight.
And secondly, India and Iran are not
neighbors today, right? We don't have a
shared border. So how do we fight?
There's a temporary artificial nation in
between. So how do we fight? Yeah, you
could fight an aerial war. Aerial war.
In an aerial war, Iran has the
advantage. Iran has thousands of
ballistic missiles, tens of hundreds of
thousands of drones
in that aerial war. Iran has the
advantage,
not India.
24 Bat says Modi, Jashankar and Dual
would never let India be vasalized. I
agree. I agree.
That's why I'm hopeful it won't happen.
Rahul says, please explain Goa
Inquisition. Why was it done? Goa
Inquisition was the brutal torture,
murder, maming and and genocide of Goan
Hindus. Why was it done? To impose
Christianity on the people. Very simple.
The aim of Christian missionaries
and and Christian
nations occupiers is to impose
Christianity on those uh who they have
conquered. The Goan Inquisition was to
was a brutal uh
and brutal act to you know brutal
institution and period of time which was
used to impose Christianity forcibly on
the people of Goa and many of them were
secretly even if they had been been
converted to Christianity they were
secretly practicing Hinduism in private
and those people were burned to death by
the by the church. So the Inquisition
was all about imposing Christianity
forcibly on the people. It was a brutal
brutal
um thing that the the Portuguese did to
us.
Rohan Sharma, thank you very much. Rohan
Sharma GI
No says Bobby says Christianity has
nothing against non-believers who and
also says Goa inquisition. Oh Goa
Inquisition is not done by Christian
missionaries. Educate sir. The Goa
Inquisition was a brutal period of time.
See who brought the Inquisition into
Goa. First of all, it was this
individual called Francis Xavier.
Some people call him St. Francis Xavier.
St. Xavier. There are all these schools
and colleges and universities. I don't
know about universities but schools and
colleges in India named after this
person. St. Xavier school, St. Xavier
College and whatnot. So this person
who was a Jesuit priest Francis Xavier,
he brought the the Spanish Inquisition,
the Portuguese Inquisition, the
Inquisition into India because Indians
who had been converted to Christianity,
they were secretly practicing their
their own culture in private, their own
religion in private,
right? So this was unacceptable. They
have to become proper Christians. So
they brought the Inquisition into India.
The Inquisition was all about
identifying those who were secret
secretly practicing Hinduism and
punishing them in the most barbaric way
possible. There was this thing called
the oto daf oto d act of faith.
Okay. Okay. O to the
let's see what it looks like. Oto.
It's about essentially burning people
alive.
Burning people alive.
Otoay in Goa.
How about that? There we have it. They
did this to our people. They burned
Indians alive in Goa. Okay, look at
this.
They also
cut the hands of thousands of people.
There is this pillar in Goa called the
hutkat stamb where these these people
their hands were chopped off and kept
right. The brutality was incredible. I
don't know how many lakhs of people may
have been killed in this but officially
only a few thousand were killed or or
only a few hundreds. You know what
happened when the Portuguese realized
that the Maratas would would defeat
them? They destroyed most of the records
of the Inquisition and they sent the
rest of the records to Rio de Janeiro in
Brazil
and only a few records are still there
in Rio de Janeiro and they are pretty
brutal but the vast majority of the
records of the Inquisition were
destroyed by the Portuguese. So imagine
how brutal it must have been that they
themselves destroyed the records.
That's the Inquisition. And the person
responsible for that was this person
called Francis Xavier.
Okay. This week again India placed
defense orders worth billions. When will
this romance of buying foreign toys end?
We need self-sufficiency ASAP. I agree
with you.
The worst thing India can do is buy
Western weapons or American weapons.
The best thing we can do is manufacture
our weapons ourselves.
As a stop gap measure, we could deal
with Russia. Russia is reliable. Well,
more reliable than the West at least.
Uh but yeah, I agree with you. We need
to be self-sufficient ASAP. Completely
agree with you. RV Matt says if Russia
oil bases are getting hit, how is India
safe? Well, it will be bad for India,
right? Because the bases that the
Russian oil bases that have been hit,
they account for about 40% of Russia's
oil exports and a lot of that is coming
to India. So, that is going to be
affected now. So Russia's exports of oil
to India are going to be badly affected
potentially. So it's bad for India.
India is not very safe. I agree it's
not.
Vir Kamat says proil proilitization
which involves claiming other religions
are false is inherently problematic and
offensive.
Bobby even supporting it is offensive to
us. Uh anyone who supports proletization
and anyone who claims that one religion
is superior to another one. I cannot
agree with that.
Right.
Especially religions that have been
responsible for genocides
to claim that such religions are are
superior to ours.
Vikas says, "I am raising a daughter
from Bangalore and what options do I
have to give her a proper non-colonial
education? Please help me understand how
can I circumvent current education
system which are largely money focused
institutions." Look,
I understand the conundrum that we face.
Uh the fact is that if you want your
daughter to have a proper, you know,
career, future, all that, she will need
to go through the education system, get
her degrees and all that, right? You
need to have
10th, 12th college degree, university
degree, etc. Depending on what you want
to do in life. So that is going to be
unfortunately necessary the given the
current state of India. But what you can
do to make sure she that her mind is not
ruined by the colonial education system.
What you can do is you can teach well
have her read the Ramayan and the
Mahabharat and learn from those you do
that it's I think it's enough right and
and make sure that she learns how to
read and write her mother tongue
whatever it is that helps for sure. So
if a child studies the Ramayan and the
Mahabharat properly over a period of
years, I think that's more than enough.
And make sure you practice your
traditions and
traditions at home. That should be
enough. Okay. All the best. All the best
to you and your daughter.
Um Mittal says, "Which top five leaders
do you consider great if you judge them
on vision, stability, and long-term
impact on their country? I now
understand why subs are superior to
career carriers, aircraft carriers.
Okay.
Which top five leaders do I consider to
be great as you mean today's leaders or
historical leaders? If you ask me about
today's leaders, the leaders of the you
know world leaders today who are great
today
who I can consider to be great today.
uh look
which which leaders um are doing a good
job. I would say it is Mr. Modi, Mr.
Putin and Mr. Shei for their respective
countries. I don't think Trump is good
doing a great job for his country. I
think he's doing a terrible job for his
country. But I think Mr. Modi, Mr. Putin
and Mr. Shi are doing the best they can
for their respective countries. Uh, I'm
sure
some, you know, things could be better
for them, but at least they they're
trying their best and they're doing a
reasonably good job
for their nations. So, I can think of
three leaders. I can't think of five
leaders. I'm sure there are more,
but I'll give you three names. I can
think of three names. Yeah. Okay.
Debashit
Mishra says, "World War has already
started or will it start in time?
predictions of what's coming for India
and the world in the near future.
Energy, economy, Indian middle class. I
don't think this is the World War II
yet. But if more nations get involved in
this, it could be World War II. If for
example European nations are dragged by
Trump into the war. If let's say for
some reason Russia and China are forced
to get involved
then it's closer to World War II than
not be because it becomes multiffront
war with nations from lots of different
parts of the world participating. That's
a world war. Right now it's still a
regional war. It's still localized. But
you are seeing now that the Ukraine war
and the Iran war are happening not
separately but it's kind of interrelated
already. So that's a concern. But it's
not World War II yet. I hope it doesn't
become World War II.
Predictions of what of what's coming for
India and the world. I think if this war
continues, there's going to be an oil
crisis, energy crisis worldwide, which
is going to be bad for economies
worldwide. is going to be bad for the
middle class worldwide including for
India right if this war ends now
then things will be perhaps
okay but if the war doesn't end if it it
continues if Hormuz remains closed if
Bab al- Mandib is closed if Russia's oil
exports are impacted by Ukraine it's
going to be a disaster for everybody
it'll be and disaster from the energy
perspective from the economic
perspective And it'll be bad for the
middle class worldwide including for
India.
Okay, I just found out about Roschill
Island. Google any Epstein links? I have
no idea whatsoever but let's find out.
Roth shield island.
What is that? Is it Antarctica? I
thought so.
So it's a 24 mile long ice covered
island in Antarctica located in the an
Australian Antarctic data center built
in sound named after Edo Alild.
This isolated Antarctic feature contains
blah blah blah blah blah.
So why is it named after the person
black rugged island?
Okay.
Why is it named after this person? In
honor of Alons James Roshield.
Okay. Um, okay. I was not aware of this
but interesting
fact.
Uh, any links? I'm not aware of any.
Godliness says in Indian parliamentary
panel says Isotch is is been sold to
private players illegally
on cheap rates. Corruption will end any
future this sovereign has what
really
is technology sold to private players
illegally?
Really?
Okay. Indian parliamentary panel found
that ISRO technology has been legally
transferred to private firms at
significantly undervalued rates. Okay,
that is a totally different thing from
illegal stuff. Okay, so it's been
legally transferred to private firms at
significantly undervalued rates.
Undervaluation.
The parliamentary committee in a March
2026 report highlighted that high-end
technologies developed with public funds
were being transferred to private firms
at undervalued rates.
Some technologies were transferred for
as as little as 6,000 rupees with others
costing about five lakhs and a few
transferred at no cost.
And who were these private players in
space in SIL?
Well, okay. I'm not aware of exactly
what this signifies and what is going
on, but looks like something is not
right and that's unfortunate.
Okay.
Pratt Dhana says on X, type
transatlantic UN vote. Google's
confused. Looks like Google is confused.
Let me see. Uh, let's go to X.
Let's go to my actual Twitter account
because Okay, give me a second. Let me
put that on the screen.
Where are we?
So, um,
let's go to X.
And what's happening here? Let's say you
transatlantic
transatlantic UN vote.
What's it say?
This is from March 26.
So,
so what was the thing? What was the vote
about?
The resolution wasn't just a
condemnation of the slave trade. It also
called for reparations and described
slavery as the gravest crime against
humanity
which some countries rejected as
creating a hierarchy of crimes over
genocide and so on. So Israel was
against it, Argentina was against it, US
was against it and who voted for it?
India voted for it. So India said that
this was
the greatest crime against humanity.
Okay. So you are clearly correct and uh
Google's AI is trying to mislead us.
Well that's fantastic.
Fantastic.
Okay.
Pratip Kumar Roy says India can never be
Iran because they have their own oil. We
don't. Well, we should look for our own
oil. I'm sure it's not impossible to
find large quantities of oil in India.
India is so large. We have such a huge
exclusive economic zone in the ocean. We
need to look for it. I'm sure we can
find more oil than what Iran has.
Pratep Kumar says, "I have seen some US
YouTube channels teaching how to make
guns. One taught how to make thermite,
fulminated mercury, military radio
gadgets, etc. Why is this allowed?"
Why is this allowed?
I have seen a YouTube video
that teaches you how to
operate stinger. missiles, anti-aircraft
missiles. These are man pads, man
portable missile defense missile
systems. A Stinger missile system is
pretty dangerous. There's a full
tutorial on YouTube. So, I don't know
why these things are there on YouTube,
but yeah, it makes no sense. You
shouldn't have such dangerous things on
YouTube. So, if you know how learn how
to make thermite, fulminating mercury,
etc. So, you can essentially learn how
to make bombs, right? I don't know why
it's allowed. should not be allowed.
Jazz says why no updates on WhatsApp
channel.
Is it important to have updates on
everything? So I have a WhatsApp
channel. I had a couple of guys working
for me who are operating that and uh
they are no longer working for me
and I think the the the credentials
remain with those people. So yeah,
anyway that's not that important. Maybe
I can start a new WhatsApp channel
perhaps if if required. We'll see.
Soldier boy says, "Search FC bill. It
will please you even more."
Okay, let's search for FC bill.
Uh, okay.
Let us see
FC bill.
FC bill. What's the new bill? Okay,
let's see. PRS India, whatever that is.
What is this? Okay, let's see quickly.
Foreign contribution.
West vesting of foreign contribution
assets in certain cases. Return of
foreign contrib. Okay. Appeals. Okay. I
don't know. This is pretty legalistic
stuff. Uh pretty dense legal text.
Implications.
Implications. What are the implications?
Let's go. Implications.
Firm directives, stringent compliance,
enlarge government control over foreign
funds and assets include mechanisms for
detailed oversight, etc., etc., etc.
Okay, it's pretty lengthy stuff, so I
will not look into it right now, but
looks like it could
please me. So, thank you for letting me
know. I'll look into it later.
Adita says, "Can India help end the Iran
war? Your thoughts?" No.
We didn't start the wars and we are not
in a position to end it. Okay. We need
to stay out of it. India
cannot help end the Iran war. The most
we can do is offer our good offices as
mediators. Nothing more than that.
When did YouTube etc. When did YouTube
add handles? If India was to take over
parts of Pakistan, how successfully
could it integrate the absorbed
population into the wider Indian
identity? unsuccessfully
you can't
the majority of the people of Pakistan
are highly radicalized against India
and you can't integrate those people
with the wider Indian Indian population
and identity so see eventually Pakist
see Pakistan is an artificial temporary
nation it will eventually break down
break up okay there's too many
centrifugal forces in Pakistan
eventually it'll break up the only
reason Pakistan doesn't break up is
because it has the the support of
foreign nations mainly the US right the
US doesn't want Pakistan to break up
that's why Pakistan remains together in
one piece so once that support goes away
Pakistan will naturally spontaneously
fragment
once that happens
India needs to somehow find a way to
dradicalize the people and that is a
process that takes decades so it's a 50
year or 100year project after that time
we can reintegrate them. Can't do it
right now. It's madness. It's suicidal.
You can't.
Okay. 24 says, "Modi has met she most
number of times than others. 20x."
Okay.
All right.
Okay. Thank you for letting me know.
Okay. Adita Achara says when it's said a
planet or star is x amount of light
years ahead how is it actually measured
and how accurate is it? There's a
concept of habitable planets one of the
biggest lie sold to mankind. Okay. So
how do we know how far a planet or star
is away? How far it is from us?
How far is a star away from us? So let's
say you have a galaxy. Okay,
let's say you have Andromeda galaxy and
you want to find out how far that is
from us. How do you do it?
In see there are various kinds of stars.
Okay,
there is a certain kind of star that's
called a standard candle and it's not a
star, it's a supernova.
How and we know exactly how much light
it emits. How does it work? You have a
neutron star which is orbiting
it's a it's a double star system. You
have a red giant and you have a neutron
star or orbiting each other the common
center of mass or it's maybe not a red
giant a standard regular star and a
neutron star together.
Now a neutron star.
No it's a white dwarf.
What is it? Neutron star. White dwarf.
Sorry.
Maybe it's a white dwarf. Standard. I
Let me just Google it. Okay. Standard
candle. It's a white dwarf. Probably
standard candle. It's a white dwarf.
Most likely, not a neutron star.
Da da da da da da da. Safi variables.
Type 1. Type 1 a supernova. White dwarf.
Exactly. White dwarf. So what happens is
you have a white dwarf with a regular
star. The white dwarf is absorbing
material from the regular star. And if
the white dwarf exceeds a certain limit
of mass because it absorbs material, it
explodes with exactly the same amount of
brightness as every other such type 1A
supernova. Okay, that's a standard
candle. So if you know exactly how
bright that light is and you know the
the correlation between distance and in
and luminosity, then you can calculate
exactly how far away that thing is. And
that's how we can find out the the uh um
the distance that a certain galaxy is
away from here. And similarly there are
different uh you know techniques used
for uh finding out the distance between
us and various galaxies, various star
systems and so on. Different techniques
for different objects.
Uh right and it's it's pretty accurate.
It's pretty accurate. Now the concept of
habitable planets is it one of the
biggest lies sold to mankind? No, it's
not. It's not. Planets can be habitable.
If you have a planet in a different star
system, okay,
that has roughly the same mass as our
planet Earth and it has a nitrogen
oxygen atmosphere that's similar to ours
and it has water, which is liquid water.
It's a habitable planet.
You could theoretically send human
beings there
and they could you you could send human
beings with uh
um you know seeds and all those things
you could plant those seeds there and I
suppose you could have life there.
So so what is the definition of a
habitable planet? It's a planet that can
sustain human life or life as we know
it. So it needs to have roughly the same
gravity as our planet which means the
same mass roughly. It needs to have
you know an atmosphere similar to ours.
Uh the density the pressure of the
atmosphere doesn't matter but it should
be an atmosphere similar to ours.
Hopefully at at one atmospheric pressure
of earth it should have liquid water and
those are the three major basic
components of what makes a habitable
planet. It typically should be in the
Goldilocks zone around its parent star
which is the the distance around the
star where you have the temperature that
is you have the right temperature for
liquid water to for water to exist in
liquid form. So that's not a lie.
It's it's true, right? It's true. But
thus far we have not been able to travel
anywhere. We were stuck on our planet.
Okay. Yeah. Nabil Sarkcar says, "How to
dispose of carbon dioxide from exhaust
sustainably and safe?" I think you need
to ask the experts. I am not an expert
in this matter. Sorry, sir. Sorry, I'm
not an expert in this.
24 Bat says in UNG vote to make food a
right only US and Israel were against.
The these nations seem to have very
strange voting patterns, right? Strange
indeed. Quite strange.
Pritik Pawar says in a completely
hypothetical situation if both the
Indian army and public support is behind
me can I carry out a coup in Delhi and
take power into my hands?
Hypothetical situation the Indian army
and public support is behind you. Can I
carry out a coup in Delhi and take power
in my hands? Difficult.
Why do I say so? Because in India,
you are right. The what you're implying
is that political power like Mao said
flows out of the barrel of a gun. Yes.
But who has the most guns in India? Is
it the military?
Nah, it's the police.
If you want to do a coup, you will need
support from the police. Who controls
the police? It's the politicians.
It'll be difficult.
Okay, you have to understand how power
really works.
Power
power power comes from the streets.
Power comes from institutions like the
police forces and so on.
Uh Tommy Veretti says, "Was
demonetization the biggest blow to
Pakistani terrorist funding?" It was a
massive blow to Pakistani terrorist
funding. For sure it was. And only now
people are beginning to realize that.
Yeah, it was indeed it was I don't know
if it was the biggest blow but it was a
major blow. Yeah.
Anik says J20 Wang way young way found
dead after removal. You can Google. I
heard about this. I heard about this. Uh
I'll look into the details later on
because it's uh I'm sure it's a rabbit
hole I will dive deep into.
But yes, I have heard about this a
couple of times in this live stream
itself. I will look into this.
Saw says why do some people in LGBT
community in India oppose BJP RSS when
RSS has been open on gay marriage but
Congress or other parties never have? I
don't know. I I don't get it.
I don't get it. It was the BJP under
Prime Minister Modi that uh decriminal
decriminalized homosexuality in India.
Since 1947, since before 1947, since the
British
imposed British laws on India, since
that time, homosexuality was a crime in
India. It was legally punishable by with
whatever punishment. It was Prime
Minister Modi's BJP. It was his
government that decriminalized
homosexuality,
right? The BJP who decriminalized
homosexuality and there are some people
in this community LGBT community that
oppose the BJP RSS
when it's the BJP that has finally given
them the right to be equal citizens.
I don't understand why it is like this.
What is the case? Why it is the case? I
don't understand the politics behind
this but it makes no sense sense to me.
It makes no sense to me.
Sidi says, "Was Nehu allowing a separate
Sharia civil law for Muslims after 1947
a terrible civilizational mistake? How
can we enforce UCCC now? Is it possible?
A separate Sharia civil law?
I I think there should be just one set
of laws for the for all the people in
the country. You can't have different
laws for different religions. Then you
have essentially different nations
within one nation. So I think that was
not a good idea. It was not a good
thing. I mean look at Turkey. Turkey
also has
you know they don't have Sharia law
uh they don't have what triple talaq and
they don't have polygamy and all in
Turkey so why can't India be like Turkey
yeah learn from Turkey I suppose so I
think that was a definitely a mistake
right uh how can we enforce UCCC now is
it possible I have no idea I don't look
into these matters I look at geopolitics
history and science these internal
matters I don't look into them so I I
can't possibly comment about that
because I'm not aware Yeah,
IPK1s says alt theory on UN sec that
gave up. USSR forced India to give it to
China because in the 1950s USSR thought
India is still an extension of the
crown. No. No.
The USSR
offered the seat to India.
Okay. The USSR was already a permanent
member of the UN Security Council. On
three different occasions, it was
offered to India. once by the USSR, once
by the US and USSR together and second,
third time also together I suppose. So
at least on one occasion it was the US
and USSR together that offered the seat
to India
and it is well documented.
It's not some theory from some from
someone's imagination. It's well
documented that both nations US and USSR
wanted India to have it but Mr. Neu said
no give it to China.
So that was that that's what really
happened. Aniket says but
decentralization gave birth to
warlordism
can give birth to warlordism.
What is this in reference to? Is this in
reference to mosaic warfare?
Look, there are risks with everything.
But if you have a unifying
civilizational identity or religious
identity or ideology or something that
properly unifies you, then there will be
no world orderism, right?
So there has to be a solution.
If you don't have a common identity,
then decentralization will give rise to
fragmentation, which could could give
rise to give rise to warlordism.
Kumar Moria says, "Will India become
like Pakistan due to corruption?" No.
Nope. Nope. Nope.
Tommy Vchetti says, "Why is open
corruption normalized in the US? Trump
making billions." I think it's a new US
now. It's a different kind of US. It's a
more imperial US where the emperor
decides what happens and the emperor
can, you know, that the rules that that
apply to others don't apply to to the
emperor and his minions. I suppose
that's what we are seeing actually right
now.
Yeah,
Subadep
Subadepari
says, "Why does the US consider Israel
such a key ally and how does how so much
influence does Israel have on the US
decisions? Why US attack Iran just
because Israel I discussed this multiple
times today, so I will not repeat it
over and over again, but I already took
this question like at least two or three
times today." Yeah. So, I've answered
it.
Achara, thank you very much. Very, very
much Adita Achara. Thank you very much.
Yashnagar
says, "How given how divided and
conflictdriven humanity still is, would
the confirmed extraterrestrial contact
change that or just intensify rivalry?"
It depends on whether the
extraterrestrial contact is just a
contact, whether it's just an
observation or it's an extraterrestrial
invasion. If it's invasion, it could
change things and and temporarily drive
humans to to cooperate irrespective of
whatever.
But even that is not guaranteed.
If there's an extraterrestrial um
invasion of of the earth, let's say
hypothetically, do you think the Jews
and the Palestinians will work together?
I I am skeptical about that.
Yeah. So, yeah, even that may not solve
the problems that we face in India.
Aditia says, "Please answer my
question." What's your question, sir?
What's your question?
The question about Israel. I answered it
like three times. Was that the question?
That question I've answered like three
times. The US is royal thing. It's
answered. If there's some other question
then you can type the question instead
of saying Singh. Please answer my
question. Okay. Uh Godliness says my
apologies for taking stating the take of
Israel has been sold illegally on cheap
rates while in reality they were sold
legally but but legally but in cheap. No
issues. No issues but something is looks
like it's fishy which is what you were
actually trying to point out which looks
like it is fishy looks like based on the
government of India report I mean
selling a technology for 5,000 rupees
6,000 rupees what are you selling
potatoes or what so yeah something seems
to be potentially fishy and that's what
you were trying to point out and I
appreciate that
Herman Bohoa says how should India deal
with a dual front shaitan bur leftist
within India Yeah,
leftist within India soft power hijack
and shaitani Akbar Pakistan overt
external hostility.
How should India deal with this?
When India needs to clean up its act
internally,
the first thing India needs to do see
these internal issues which are
which are orchestrated by outsiders,
right?
India needs to clean up its act
internally.
First thing, expel all illegal
infiltrators from Indian territory.
There must be tens of millions of
Bangladeshes within India. Everyone
knows where they are. You can see them
every day. But the government of India
does nothing about them. I wonder why.
Expel them all out of India. All illegal
infiltrators. Whether they are
Bangladeshies, whether they are
Pakistanis, whether they are cookies,
whether they are Rohindas, expel them
all. That way that internal
fifth front or whatever it is will will
not long will no longer be there.
Secondly, crack down on all missionary
activity in India.
If somebody wants to convert to a
foreign religion voluntarily of their
own inner desire, let them do it.
Nothing wrong with that. But this
artificial
industrial scale demographic
re-engineering
you know project or projects that the
foreign powers are running within India
those have to be stopped
when it come so these are some of the
things we can do about shaitan bazorg
when it when it comes to Pakistan we
just have to stockpile our missiles and
drones and when the time comes
blitzkrieg
72 hours wars maximum.
Pratep Kumar Roy says, "Sometimes I feel
like I'm watching a test match while
watching your live streams. Early 2000
memories." Yeah, I know. A test match
generally lasts six hours, right? A
session. I mean, a day and you have a
lunch break and tea break in between.
Lunch break is about 45 minutes, 50
minutes. Tea break is like 20 minutes.
So, it's about 7 hours long. And this
live stream is already 4 hours 37
minutes long. So it's approaching test
match test match magnitude now.
Okay. IPK vaness says YouTube channel le
real talk expose that CCP asset Jang
Lelay real talk. Okay. Okay. Jang
you mean the the professor
the professor that professor who is very
famous these days. Okay. All right. I'm
not aware of that but all right.
MK for MKkesh Kumar says Jahind
Ukraine Russia war best struggle Israel
US Iran Asia suffers winters versus
summers LPG shortage and imagine
inductions
join ACs
this April okay if there's an LPG
shortage you'll have induction heaters
that people will have to use right
electricity so this and this summer
there's going to be everybody will be
using ACES obviously because it's hot in
summer so there's there's going to be a
surge in demand for electricity which is
going to you know put additional stress
and and and additional burden on India's
electricity grid. So the demand for
electricity will rise and I hope that
doesn't uh cause problems. So yeah yes
yes
these are real issues we're going to
potentially have to face very soon. I
hope the government is prepared for it.
Pratep Kumar Royce says Pratep Kumar
says how to create a black hole. No
YouTube videos found. It's very simple
how to create a black hole.
You take an object.
Okay, let's say it's 1 g.
Okay, 1 g. You calculate its schwatz
shield radius.
The swatch radius is given by R is equal
to 2 mg by C^². R is equal to 2
mg / C ^ 2 where M is the mass of your
object. G capital G is Newton's
gravitational constant. and C is the
speed of light. 2 mg by C² is R the
short radius of your object. So if it's
1 g, what is the short radius? Let's
let's calculate the short radius of a 1
g object. Let's ask Google.
I'll not calculate myself. I'll ask the
AI. What is the short shield radius of a
1 g object?
Calculate.
It's about 1.48 * 10 - 30 m. Okay. 10 to
-30. So that's definitely bigger than
the plank length actually, which is
nice.
Um,
yeah. So all you have to do is you take
your 1 g object and you cram it into a
space
of smaller than 10 - 30 m. That's how
you create a black hole. As simple as
that. If it's 1 kilo 1,000 g, it's going
to be you have to cram that 1 kilo
object into a space of of roughly 10 to
minus 27 m in diameter. You can do that.
You're going to have yourself a black
hole. As simple as that. The the the
trick is to find the the strength to
squeeze that 1 kilo thing into that
small space.
Yeah. Okay. Mavin says BJP doing great
in geopolitics but terrible internally.
I could not comment about what's
happening internally. So, okay. All
right, sir. Men, good to see you.
Okay. Sayan Majublar says, "Your
thoughts on the proposed national aero
test center. Can it end reliance on
foreign testing of coverage jet engine
in high altitude trials?" See what we
need is a dedicated test bed which is an
aircraft on it's it's a test aircraft on
which you can attach
engines that you're testing. So
typically that sort of aircraft will
have four engines and one of the engines
is the one you're testing. So even if it
fails or whatever the aircraft will keep
flying because it it's got three other
engines. That's what you do. So that's
the kind of aircraft we need so that we
can actually test our jet engines not in
a lab but up there in on in altitude to
take it to whatever altitude you want,
whatever speed you want and test it out
there. That's what we need right now. We
are I think we are relying on Russian um
you know Russian help for this.
So if we have a propo national aero test
center with these facilities, it'll be
fantastic for India. It'll be great.
Pratipar Roy says what is more dangerous
black hole pulsar neutron star or
exoplanets like wasp wasp 1b
what any of these things see a black
hole is dangerous if it's in your
vicinity and you have cross the the
event horizon then it's then it's
curtains for you but if it's lurking
somewhere nearby it's not going to be
dangerous for you it's not a vacuum
cleaner that is going to you know re
reach out to you and suck you in it's
not like that you replace the sun with a
black hole the only thing that will
change is that we will have no more
light here it'll freeze but the planets
will not be sucked into the sun into the
black hole if the black hole is exactly
where the sun is. So black holes are not
inherently dangerous as such. Pulsars
not dangerous
unless they you're right next to them
then it's going to be a problem for you.
Uh neutron stars once again not
dangerous unless you're right next to
them or you collide into one
exoplanets.
Don't go to one of these exoplanets and
you're fine. I don't know what was 1b
is, but 12b is, but I'm sure it's pretty
interesting. Shall we see? Let's see.
What is this exoplanet? Wasp 12b.
What is that? Extreme hot Jupiter. Okay,
it's a hot Jupiter. That's a certain
class, a certain category of exoplanets
which is a gas giant which is orbiting
very close to its parent star. So, one
side is super hot, other side is super
cold. There's tremendous hurricane level
winds going on over there and it's
evaporating rapidly. So that's a hot
Jupiter. See don't go to any of these
places then you are perfectly safe.
Okay. Polomial says cousin in 30 is
alcoholism. Any advice from Hinduism? I
I don't know what advice to give from
Hinduism.
I don't know. Uh, I would say take your
cousin to a to a reputed detoxification
center and and and make sure that he or
she goes through the whole course
and uh
and I don't I don't know how to deal
with alcoholism. I and so yeah, I don't
know. I I think you will need advice
from experts in this matter. I am not
the right person to give any kind of
advice in these situations. Okay. Um and
I don't know I'm sure there is good
advice that comes out of Hinduism but I
I'm not aware of it. Yeah. So I can't
say I'm very sorry to hear this. Please
take care of your cousin and take him or
her to the right right expert and seek
professional help
and yeah hope I hope it turns out well
for your cousin. Okay all the best.
Pratipar Roy says is life possible on
exoplanets like Kepler 453
look I don't know
let me see one by one what these things
are
Kepler 452b
so 452b I said B
a super earth okay how large super earth
means it's a earthlike rocky planet but
it's much larger than the earth and no
no I'm not watching this it's about 1.5
5 1.6 larger in diameter. Okay. Uh is it
in the Goldilock zone? Yeah, habitable
zone where liquid water could could
exist. So potentially, okay, it's 10%
older than Earth. It may be potentially
it looks like there is a chance that
there could be life on Kepler 452b.
Okay. What is key to
um 18b
super Earth? Once again, it's a super
Earth. It's larger than the Earth, but
it's rocky. It's 8.6 times as massive as
the Earth. So the gravity is way way
more powerful on this planet than Earth.
Carbon bearing molecules they found
methane carbon dioxide
it's a it could be a water covered
highen world. There could potentially be
life on this planet for sure. Absolutely
sure that there could be life on this
planet. Very interesting. It's a water
world but it's super earth. So it's not
rocky. It's a water earth and it's very
very large but almost nine times as
large as our planet. massive as our
planet. Okay. Proxima Centtory B.
Proxima Centuri B.
Let's see what's this like. Uh Rocky
super Earth 1.27 Earth masses orbiting
within the within the habitable zone of
its red dwarf star. H good. Yeah, it's a
good candidate.
We don't know if there is water. It it
we don't know if it has an atmosphere
there. But Proxima Centtor is a flare
star which is a problem. So yeah, I
think it's less likely for life to exist
on this planet because it's host star is
a player star. Okay, what about
Trappist 1e?
What do we have here? Rocky earth-sized
exoplanet. Wow. Goldilock zone of the
red dwarf star Trappist one. I think
it's a prime candidate for habitability.
It's an earth-sized guy. It's in the
Goldilock zone
and it's Oh, it's tidily locked. It's
tid tidily locked with its star, which
means it's a little trickier there, but
still think it's a good candidate.
Kepler 62F
potentially habitable super Earth. So,
how 40% larger than Earth. It's rocky
most likely and it's within the
habitable zone. So these are all good
candidates at least decent candidates
for a potential the potential existence
of life.
Pratep Kumar Roy says hydration
reminder. Good night everyone. Good
night. Thank you very much for the
reminder. I shall soon end this now.
Djamat says Bobby Epen says hundreds of
millions killed throughout history in
the name of Christian teachings are due
to imperfect humans. Why didn't
imperfect humans do so in the name of
Jane's? Janism, Buddhism, etc. Um,
I wouldn't know.
We know that
um there were no killings in the name of
Hinduism, Jinism, Buddhism.
There was no oppression or persecution
or colonization in the name
under the under the pretext of following
Hinduism, Buddhism, Janism, Sikism,
Shinto,
Tangism, Zoroastrianism,
right? Never happened.
So that's a good question you were
asking, sir. Dirk Kamad, good question
you're asking.
Rahul says why and how Christian texts
are used to justify crusades.
Look, I am not an expert in
Christianity, but I think Christianity
believes that they their God is the only
God, the only true God and everybody I
think that the church, the Catholic
church has in the past said that you
know any human being who does not
worship Jesus Christ is destined for
hell and is is an inferior human being
and is is a non-person or something and
you know
it's it's perfectly just justified to to
enslave them, behead them, kill them,
steal their land, steal their property,
all of that. So because they don't
worship the true god that sort of thing.
I think that was the justification.
Aida Singh says we don't want everything
at the same time. We want things over
time gradually. So please take care of
your health and sleep on time. Maybe
postpone the super chats to next stream.
Well, this is the last super chat for
today. So thank you very much. Thank you
very much. Yeah, I agree. It's it's uh
it's 4 hours 50 minutes almost.
So I shall now take your leave. Thank
you Abida Singh for this and this is the
last supercharge for the day. No more
for today. Thank you very much
everybody. It's been a very long live
stream almost 5 hours. Thank you so much
everybody. Take care. I will see you in
tomorrow's live stream. We will discuss
more of what's happening. Until then
take care. Keep asking questions. Keep
raising your standards. Keep learning.
I'll see you very soon tomorrow. Take
care. Good night. Good day. Bye-bye for
now.